<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GDquest</title>
    <link>http://gdquest.com/tags/krita-brushes/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on GDquest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://gdquest.com/tags/krita-brushes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Krita brushes for game artists</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/krita-brushes-for-game-artists</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/krita-brushes-for-game-artists</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Version 9 (&lt;em&gt;Dec 2016&lt;/em&gt;) contains (Standard version):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;57 unique brush presets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 pdf documents&lt;/strong&gt; to help you get started with the brushes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monthly updates&lt;/strong&gt;. More brushes and videos are already on your way!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The premium tier adds:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More than 30 minutes of exclusive video tutorials&lt;/strong&gt; to get the most out of the brushes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;natural media brushkit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Priority support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take my time to design the presets and ensure that they are worth adding to the pack. I also use them in my daily work to ensure that they are tested thoroughly in all kinds of configurations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-other-artists-have-to-say&#34;&gt;What other artists have to say&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/page/krita-brushes/testimonial-zhillustrator.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Thumbnails painted with Krita by Živko Kondić&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/zhille&#34;&gt;Zhillustrator&lt;/a&gt; writes: &amp;laquo;Nathan&amp;rsquo;s brush set has some essential brushes for digital painting that will ease your way into Krita&amp;rsquo;s powerful brush engine. My favorites in the pack are the mix and smudge brushes. Honestly, if you like the Lite set, it&amp;rsquo;s worth it, Krita is going somewhere.&amp;raquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See more of Zhillustrator&amp;rsquo;s work &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artstation.com/artist/zhille&#34;&gt;on Artstation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gum.co/krita-brushes-gdquest-lite&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/page/krita-brushes/krita-brushes-banner-lite.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Krita brushes banner lite&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lite-version-span-class-text-success-free-span&#34;&gt;Lite version &lt;span class=&#34;text--success&#34;&gt;(free)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know the best part? There is actually a free, smaller version of this set, so you can try it out for yourself.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gumroad.com/l/krita-brushes-gdquest-lite&#34;&gt;Click here to download the free Krita brushes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;changelog&#34;&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;version-9-dec-2016&#34;&gt;Version 9 - Dec 2016&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 new presets including a blur tool, splatter brushes, and a rock texture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 natural media presets, and especially a powerful cloud painting tool (premium)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a new tutorial on cloud painting (premium)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;version-8-nov-2016&#34;&gt;Version 8 - Nov 2016&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 textured rock brushes: these presets will allow you to add 2 types of sharp grain to your rocks, for a more believable look.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smear cloud: whether you want to slightly blur or completely diffuse your edges, this is a very efficient preset to do so. It blurs your painting fast and provides very good control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smoke dusty: this brush can be used for both clouds and smoke. Unlike the existing cloud builder brushes, it offers some high frequency details for a richer look.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 water brushes: the first water brushes are in! They&amp;rsquo;re useful to paint waves, for a lake, a sea or an ocean.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tree leaves builder: a nice brush to quickly add detailed leaves to a piece of concept art.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;version-7-oct-2016&#34;&gt;Version 7 (Oct 2016)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Rock presets: draw small, round and stylized rocks with Rock_builder_stylized, and detail them with the Rock_detail brush&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 special presets for shading: the special_shadow brush allows you to stamp simple round shadows, to place under characters and small assets. The other 2 brushes are directional shading brushes, with a sharp and a soft side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 pencil-looking brushes: one for sketching, and one for shading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated paint_old preset: I remade the preset from scratch. It is at least twice as fast, and strokes are more consistent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;version-6-sep-2016&#34;&gt;Version 6 (Sep 2016)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 pixel art deform tools: pixel art-friendly Grow, Shrink, Move and Swirl tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cloud builder brushes: the first builders are here! These presets will help you paint accurate sprite silhouettes in no time. These will work for both stylized and realistic clouds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 smoke brushes: for when you need to achieve a textured smoky effect. Also useful to add definition to materials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text-based install guide (pdf)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An intro to brush families (pdf)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the full release changelog, check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gumroad.com/l/krita-brushes-for-game-artists&#34;&gt;Gumroad page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>