<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Game Design Quest</title>
    <link>http://gdquest.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Game Design Quest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 10:08:53 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://gdquest.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommended graphic tablets</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/recommended-graphic-tablets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 10:08:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/recommended-graphic-tablets/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/hardware/huion-vs-wacom.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Huion vs Wacom graphic tablet banner&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;recommended-graphic-tablets:fe04af95515442dc424d63ca1b599889&#34;&gt;Recommended graphic tablets&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this page, you can find a list of the graphic tablets I recommend for &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/&#34;&gt;Game Art Quest&lt;/a&gt;. I used &lt;a href=&#34;http://frenden.com/tagged/review&#34;&gt;Frenden&amp;rsquo;s reviews&lt;/a&gt; as a reference to pick affordable tablets you can try out. I also asked feedback to fellow professionals who use Huion devices, as I only have Wacom tablets here. When you buy a graphic tablet, be sure to test your device and to use your right of withdrawal in case you don&amp;rsquo;t like it. And read reviews on Amazon or on the website you&amp;rsquo;re buying them on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;flat-tablets:fe04af95515442dc424d63ca1b599889&#34;&gt;Flat tablets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flat tablets are perfect for everyone to start with at a low price. Especially students and hobbyists.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huion H610 pro (80$) - &lt;a href=&#34;http://frenden.com/post/87110791272/huion-h610-pro-h610-k58-graphics-tablet-review&#34;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wacom Intuos Pro Medium or Large (300-500$)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;screen-tablets:fe04af95515442dc424d63ca1b599889&#34;&gt;Screen tablets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Screen tablets are worth a try if you&amp;rsquo;re an experienced artist already, and you do a lot of line work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huion GT-220 (21.5&amp;raquo; HD screen, 800$) - &lt;a href=&#34;http://frenden.com/image/118056589592&#34;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monoprice 19&amp;raquo; (1440*900 resolution, 400$) - &lt;a href=&#34;http://frenden.com/post/69444810884/review-monoprice-19-tablet-monitor-wacom-take&#34;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wacom Cintiq 13HD (13&amp;raquo; HD screen, 800$)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tips:fe04af95515442dc424d63ca1b599889&#34;&gt;Tips&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always&lt;/strong&gt; download and install the driver from the manufacturer&amp;rsquo;s official website &lt;strong&gt;before&lt;/strong&gt; you plug your device in! This will save you some trouble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As far as Wacom tablets are concerned, you can pretty safely buy second hand devices! That&amp;rsquo;s how I got mine, and after years of frequent use, they still work perfectly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the time I&amp;rsquo;m writing this, Krita doesn&amp;rsquo;t support every single tablet on the market. The developers are in the process of re-writing their tablet code. Wacom tablets work OK, but some other brands might not until Krita 3.0&amp;rsquo;s release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to use 2 tablets at the same time like I&amp;rsquo;m doing, they have to share the same brand. In other words, you can&amp;rsquo;t use a flat Wacom tablet and a Wacom cintiq at the same time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAQ brush set</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/brush-pack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/brush-pack/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;!-- PAGE NAVIGATION --&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-brushes&#34;&gt;
      &lt;button type=&#34;button&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-default btn-lg&#34;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-paint-brush text-success&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; The brushes
      &lt;/button&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;

    &lt;a href=&#34;#installation-guide&#34;&gt;
      &lt;button type=&#34;button&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-default btn-lg&#34;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-file text-info&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Installation guide
      &lt;/button&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;

    &lt;a href=&#34;#faq&#34;&gt;
      &lt;button type=&#34;button&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-default btn-lg&#34;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-question text-info&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; FAQ
      &lt;/button&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;!-- &lt;button type=&#34;button&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-default btn-lg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-dollar text-success&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Buy the brushes!
    &lt;/button&gt; --&gt;
    &lt;script src=&#34;https://gumroad.com/js/gumroad.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;a class=&#34;gumroad-button&#34; href=&#34;https://gum.co/game-art-quest-brush-pack&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Buy the brushes!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- Pills example --&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;ul class=&#34;nav nav-pills nav-justified&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;Menu 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;Menu 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;Menu 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt; --&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-brushes&#34;&gt;The Game Art Quest Krita brushes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;thumbnail-pack 0-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;GAQ Krita brushes thumbnail&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive center-block&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Game Art Quest Krita brush pack was made for the backers of the eponymous &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/gdquest/game-art-quest-make-professional-2d-art-with-krita&#34;&gt;Kickstarter campaign&lt;/a&gt;. It is made by a 2d game artist, for game artists. Specifically, for people who create in-game assets. It also works great for digital painters in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It follows a few key concepts. The goal is to help you to work &lt;strong&gt;fast&lt;/strong&gt;, and to allow you to &lt;strong&gt;focus on your art&lt;/strong&gt;. It is a bloat free pack, filled with efficient drawing tools. I favor versatile tools and avoid brush redundancy so you don’t have to keep switching between them to achieve a variety of effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The presets are dry for the most part, so you can easily apply thick paint on the canvas. Need a softer blending effect? Use the I and O keys to tweak your opacity and make the brushes weaker. I am slowly building the pack as I draw all sorts of game assets and encounter new challenges. That way, I get to use every single preset in my work and to proof-test them in depth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first version features 6 blending and smearing brushes. Over time, I will add basic drawing and shading tools as well as reusable textured brushes to help you paint elements of nature faster (clouds, leaves, rocks…).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how each family of presets works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;blending-paintbrushes&#34;&gt;Blending paintbrushes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;blending-paintbrushes.png&#34; alt=&#34;Blending paintbrushes thumbnail&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive center-block&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those presets are the most flexible ones in the set. They allow you to add color to the canvas, to blend colors together, and to achieve both dry and wet painting effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you select the brush presets, the painting effect is at its maximum intensity. If you want to make it softer, you have to lower the opacity by pressing the I key 1 to 3 times. This will both reduce the amount of paint that is added to the canvas and make the blending effect duller. If you want to make the brush dry again, press the O key to increase the opacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those brushes don’t work like usual pixel brushes with blending modes. To lighten, darken, recolor or erase pixels, use a basic brush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strengths:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can apply both dry and wet paint on the canvas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can both push paint and blend colors on the canvas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficient from the blocking to polishing stage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weaknesses:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gives your work a painterly quality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inefficient with blending modes other than normal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bad when used as an eraser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;smear-brushes&#34;&gt;Smear brushes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;smear-brushes.png&#34; alt=&#34;Smear brushes thumbnail&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive center-block&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The smear brushes pull, push and blur pixels on the canvas. They behave a bit like your finger on charcoal or acrylic paint. They are a bit special and sometimes pointed out as bad tools by digital artists. The reason is that you can’t use them randomly. When you want to smear, you have to know exactly what you are doing. Those brushes can produce ugly results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 2 use cases that I recommend. You can use them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To sculpt the silhouette of an object&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or to blur out and pull edges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;smear-effect.png&#34; alt=&#34;Smear effect example&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive center-block&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are specific cases when you can use them for shading, but mastering those presets will take a lot of practice. As they blur pixels, they will remove details in your painting. If that’s not what you’re after, they won’t work for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I designed those presets so that they don’t apply any color on the canvas. They will only modify existing pixels. Hence you can use them to sculpt silhouettes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strengths:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can push, pull and soften edges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weaknesses:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removes details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Needs practice to master&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;thumbnails&#34;&gt;Thumbnails&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brush thumbnails are color-coded and follow Krita’s guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pink brushes use the color smudge engine in dulling mode. The strokes can both add paint on the canvas and blend with existing colors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue brushes use the color smudge engine in smearing mode. They drag existing pixels on the canvas, a bit like the finger tool in other drawing applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example brush stroke is here to give you a sense of what each preset does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A completely white stroke means that the preset doesn’t add color on the canvas. It only moves existing pixels around or blends them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pictogram might be visible on the thumbnail. They are here to help you find certain types of brushes faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The water droplet is for blending brushes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The finger indicates that the preset moves existing pixels on the canvas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;installation-guide&#34;&gt;Installation guide&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-arrow-right
text-info
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 The brushes come as a bundle. To install them, go to the &lt;strong&gt;Settings menu&lt;/strong&gt;, and to &lt;strong&gt;Manage Resources&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;installation-guide/1-settings-menu.png&#34; alt=&#34;Installation guide step 1&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive center-block&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-arrow-right
text-info
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 On the window that pops up, click on &lt;strong&gt;Import bundle/resources&lt;/strong&gt; in the top right corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;installation-guide/2-manage-resources.png&#34; alt=&#34;Installation guide step 2&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive center-block&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-arrow-right
text-info
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;strong&gt;Locate the bundle file on your computer&lt;/strong&gt;, confirm, and you will see it pop up in the Active Bundles tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;installation-guide/3-import-bundle.png&#34; alt=&#34;Installation guide step 3&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive center-block&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-arrow-right
text-info
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;strong&gt;Click on the OK button&lt;/strong&gt; at the bottom of the window to save your changes. The brushes are now available in the brush preset panel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;installation-guide/4-confirm-changes.png&#34; alt=&#34;Installation guide step 4&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive center-block&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;faq&#34;&gt;Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;hugoshortcode-8-why-are-there-no-fx-preset&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-question-circle
text-info
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 Why are there no FX preset?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pack doesn’t feature “FX” presets, that is to say variations of existing brushes set to a certain blending mode, to lighten or darken your pixels for instance. All of the most important blending modes have a keyboard shortcut by default in Krita. It is faster to use a key combination than load a different brush preset every time you need to change your blending mode. Also, there are many useful combinations of brush shapes and blending modes. Covering them all would make the set super heavy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDquest news and Krita 3.0 pre-alpha 3</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/community/GDquest-news-and-Krita-3.0-pre-alpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 08:25:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/community/GDquest-news-and-Krita-3.0-pre-alpha/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/JWwpm4hs0l0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Hi there! I wanted to keep you posted on what is going on right now with GDquest. The video says it all, but I’m going to sum up the news below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With one last contract finished last week, and the series on monster design done, I am now working full-time on Game Art Quest. My top priority is to release the first version of the GAQ Krita brush back and to finish chapter 0 in the training. Once this is done, I will start releasing videos from the training publicly, at the rate of 1 to 2 per week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I released the first 5 soundtracks from the project in an album called &lt;a href=&#34;https://gdquest.bandcamp.com/album/space-adventures&#34;&gt;Space Adventures&lt;/a&gt;. They are available under the &lt;strong&gt;Creative Commons 4.0 license&lt;/strong&gt;, so you can use them in &lt;strong&gt;both personal and commercial projects&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&#34;border: 0; width: 700px; height: 307px;&#34; src=&#34;https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1579881958/size=large/bgcol=333333/linkcol=e99708/artwork=small/transparent=true/&#34; seamless&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.bandcamp.com/album/space-adventures&#34;&gt;Space adventures by Nathan Lovato&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-votes-for-future-tutorials:0ffd5e13c63a8bd067949ade6a42b50e&#34;&gt;Your votes for future tutorials&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since January, I have been &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/post/community/vote-for-upcoming-tutorials-january-2016/&#34;&gt;running a vote&lt;/a&gt; to ask you which tutorial series you wanted me to do this year aside from Krita. More than 400 people voted, and here are the themes you picked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview of Godot 2.0, the open source game engine, for 2d games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Painting rock and grass tiles for 2d games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Human proportions, from reality to games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is great, as they will reinforce &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/&#34;&gt;Game Art Quest&lt;/a&gt;. I might also do the 4th one, the Overview of &lt;a href=&#34;http://superpowers-html5.com/&#34;&gt;Superpowers, the collaborative HTML5 game engine&lt;/a&gt;, as time permits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;krita-3-0-pre-alpha-3:0ffd5e13c63a8bd067949ade6a42b50e&#34;&gt;Krita 3.0, pre-alpha 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;\img\post\community\krita-gradient-map.png&#34; alt=&#34;Krita gradient map filter&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 3rd pre-alpha of Krita 3.0 was released! The development entered a feature-frozen state, and the full release of Krita 3.0 is planned for April 27. The features that didn’t make it in this version will be available in Krita 3.1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick list of what is new in this pre-alpha:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The improvements to the layer docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new grid and guides system, along with snapping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A gradient map filter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A greater alpha blending mode, useful for painting with the pixel brush engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The foundations for 2 exporters. One is for spriter, the animation application for 2d games, and the other one is a csv-based format to exports animated sequences from krita.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A variety of improvements to the move tool, the crop tool, the assistants…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Head on to the dedicated article on the official website to find the builds along with download instructions. It also features an exhaustive list of changes in this version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That’s it for this update. See you soon, in the next one!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Art Quest Vol. 1 - Krita</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/volume-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/volume-1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;game-art-quest-volume-1-learn-to-use-krita-for-professional-game-art&#34;&gt;Game Art Quest volume 1 - Learn to use Krita for professional game art&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page is a living document for the 1st volume of Game Art Quest. This means that everything listed here is subject to change, based on your feedback primarily. Below, you will find the course outline .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-how-to-get-the-most-out-of-the-training&#34;&gt;Introduction: How to get the most out of the training&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Installing Krita on Windows&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating your first document and Troubleshooting common issues&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to take the most out of the course&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Toolbox - extra resources to add to the training&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction to graphic tablets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to setup a Wacom tablet for digital art&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assignment 1: 5 line drawing exercises&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick look at &lt;a href=&#34;http://picasa.google.com/&#34;&gt;Picasa&lt;/a&gt;
Quick look at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pureref.com/&#34;&gt;PureRef&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1-overview-of-krita&#34;&gt;Chapter 1: Overview of Krita&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea behind this first chapter is to make you comfortable with the application in as little time as possible. It focuses only on the most important tools you&amp;rsquo;ll need to produce your art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quickstart Guide Chapter Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting to know the UI&lt;/strong&gt;: Understanding the various parts of the interface, the philosophy behind Krita&amp;rsquo;s design, the dockers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Navigation on the canvas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Painting with the freehand brush tool&lt;/strong&gt;: brushes can do a lot of things in Krita, so I&amp;rsquo;ll try to give you a quick sense of how they work. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how Krita can turn every single brush into an eraser. We&amp;rsquo;ll also learn how to use the alpha lock painting mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Picking colors and using the pop-up palette&lt;/strong&gt;: this shortcut wheel allows you to quickly switch between the background and foreground colors, to pick colors, to access a history of the last used colors and brush presets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An introduction to layers&lt;/strong&gt;: the layer docker is being changed a lot in Krita 3, so we&amp;rsquo;ll just look at the basics here. We&amp;rsquo;ll learn to create layers, groups, to rename them, to toggle visibility, and also we&amp;rsquo;ll see how we can pick a layer from the canvas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working with selections&lt;/strong&gt;: we&amp;rsquo;ll focus on the most common operations with the outline, contiguous, square and elliptical selection tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Filling outlines and selections&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Move tool and free transform&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting your own shortcuts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-2-the-2d-game-asset-worklow&#34;&gt;Chapter 2: the 2d game asset worklow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This second chapter provides an introduction to the game art workflow with Krita. It explains the iterative nature of game art, as well as the broad steps involved in creating original game assets, from design to the finished product. I will also provide you with an example to show you which tools I use the most, and how I&amp;rsquo;ve adapted my workflow to Krita.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2d Game art vs Illustration: what&amp;rsquo;s the difference?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview of the game asset painting workflow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The game asset workflow: sketching thumbnails&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sketching tricks with Krita&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blocking a game sprite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Refining or bringing out the spirit of an asset&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Techniques to refine a painting with Krita&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polishing sprites&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-3-diving-deeper&#34;&gt;Chapter 3: diving deeper&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application offers a wealth of unexpected features. Powerful deformations, wrap-around mode, flexible brush engines, drawing assistants, filter layers, and much more! In this chapter, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at some of the more advanced functions Krita offers, as well as how to use them in practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll specifically look at the tools that will not change in Krita 3.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-4-new-features-and-changes-in-krita-3&#34;&gt;Chapter 4: New features and changes in Krita 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Chapter 5: Animation &lt;small&gt;with Krita 3&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>course</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/volume-1/course/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 17:55:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/volume-1/course/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome:ad791bfd9ad64307d23668dd1a2ed4a4&#34;&gt;Welcome!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page is hidden on the website. It is not protected, as it will be released publicly eventually. But as you made the campaign possible, you get to see the videos before everybody else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The page is a continuous work in progress. If you have any questions, comments and suggestions, either contact me or comment on the Youtube videos!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugoshortcode-1-links:ad791bfd9ad64307d23668dd1a2ed4a4&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-link
text-default
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 Links&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GDquest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-facebook
text-info
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/GameArtQuest/&#34;&gt;Facebook study group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-paint-brush
text-info
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/brush-pack/&#34;&gt;GAQ Krita brush pack&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-dollar
text-success
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pureref.com/&#34;&gt;Pureref&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Win, Mac, Linux&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/picasa/&#34;&gt;Picasa&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Win, Mac, development discontinued&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extra learning resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-mortar-board
text-info
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ctrlpaint.com/library/&#34;&gt;CtrlPaint&lt;/a&gt; - Digital art tutorials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-mortar-board
text-info
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/user/ProkoTV&#34;&gt;Proko&lt;/a&gt; - Human drawing and anatomy courses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-book
text-info
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;a href=&#34;http://louvus.com/&#34;&gt;Digital Painting with Krita 2.9&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-dollar
text-success
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/portfolio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- TOP PICTURES --&gt;
&lt;!-- Add a carousel? --&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;section&#34; id=portfolio-header-pictures&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;container&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-4 col-md-4 col-sm-4 col-xs-6&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;Content/Header/gdquest_portfolio_magicfred_kiwitiki_submarine.png&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Kiwitiki&#39;s Submarine&#34;&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-4 col-md-4 col-sm-4 col-xs-6&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;Content/Header/gdquest-portfolio-Dan-The-Rabbit.jpg&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Dan the Rabbit&#34;&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-4 col-md-4 col-sm-4 col-xs-6 hidden-xs&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;Content/Header/gdquest-portfolio-The-Lumberjack.jpg&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;The Lumberjack&#34;&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;section&#34; id=&#34;we-make-games&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;container&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;col-md-12&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;banner-we-make-games.png&#34; alt=&#34;We Make Games!&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive center-block&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-4 col-md-4 col-sm-4 col-xs-12 text-center&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-3x fa-code fa-fw text-warning&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;p class=&#34;text-left&#34;&gt;We can answer your need for HTML5 and Unity game development. For Html5, we use
          &lt;strong&gt;our open source game engine Meta2d&lt;/strong&gt;, offering clean and easy to edit code.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-4 col-md-4 col-sm-4 col-xs-12 text-center&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-3x fa-fw fa-paint-brush text-info&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;p class=&#34;text-left&#34;&gt;We design
          &lt;strong&gt;appealing characters and environments, clear UI elements and polished cut-out animations&lt;/strong&gt; made with Spine or Photoshop to serve your creative vision.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-4 col-md-4 col-sm-4 col-xs-12 text-center&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-3x fa-fw fa-youtube-play text-danger&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;p class=&#34;text-left&#34;&gt;We have a library of
          &lt;strong&gt;dozens of deep and instructive tutorials&lt;/strong&gt; to prove our expertise. Find them all on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/c/gdquest&#34;&gt;GDquest youtube channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:nathan.lovato.art@gmail.com&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;button-hire-us.png&#34; alt=&#34;Hire Us!&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive center-block&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- THE TEAM --&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;section&#34; id=&#34;portfolio-the-team&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;container&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;banner-the-team.png&#34; alt=&#34;The Team&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive center-block&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-3 col-md-3 col-sm-6 col-xs-6&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;Avatars/avatar-nathan.png&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive center-block&#34;&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Nathan Lovato - Game Designer&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
          &lt;strong&gt;Nathan&lt;/strong&gt; is the author of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtube.com/c/gdquest&#34;&gt;GDquest Youtube channel&lt;/a&gt;. He is both a professional designer and a tutor.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-3 col-md-3 col-sm-6 col-xs-6&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;Avatars/avatar-magicfred.png&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive center-block&#34;&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;MagicFred - Game Artist&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;MagicFred is a game artist with more than 15 years working in the industry. Founder of Dijiko, he designed and released a variety of games on web and mobile platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-3 col-md-3 col-sm-6 col-xs-6&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;Avatars/avatar-arthur.png&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive center-block&#34;&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Arthur Shefer - Developer&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Arthur is the author of the open source JS game engine meta2d. He worked on the top grossing web and mobile game My Country as a front end developer.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-3 col-md-3 col-sm-6 col-xs-6&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;Avatars/avatar-clement.png&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive center-block&#34;&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Clement Brard - Developer&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Clément is a Unity developer with more than 5 years of experience. He is the author of Lord of the Dungeon.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;script type=&#34;text/javascript&#34;&gt;
for (var i = 1; i &lt; 11; i++) {
  var img = document.createElement(&#39;img&#39;);
  img.src = document.URL + &#34;/content/gdquest-game-design-portfolio-&#34; + i + &#34;.png&#34;;

  console.log(img);
  $(&#39;#portfolio-gallery&#39;).append(img)
}
&lt;/script&gt; --&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;section&#34; id=&#34;portfolio-gallery&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;container&#34;&gt;


    &lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-4 col-md-4 col-sm-4 col-xs-6&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;Content/gdquest-game-design-portfolio-4.png&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Kiwitiki&#39;s Submarine&#34;&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-4 col-md-4 col-sm-4 col-xs-6&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;Content/gdquest-game-design-portfolio-5.png&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Kiwitiki&#39;s Submarine&#34;&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-4 col-md-4 col-sm-4 col-xs-6&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;Content/gdquest-game-design-portfolio-6.png&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Kiwitiki&#39;s Submarine&#34;&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-4 col-md-4 col-sm-4 col-xs-6&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;Content/gdquest-game-design-portfolio-7.png&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Kiwitiki&#39;s Submarine&#34;&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-4 col-md-4 col-sm-4 col-xs-6&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;Content/gdquest-game-design-portfolio-8.png&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Kiwitiki&#39;s Submarine&#34;&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-4 col-md-4 col-sm-4 col-xs-6&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;Content/gdquest-game-design-portfolio-9.png&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Kiwitiki&#39;s Submarine&#34;&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-4 col-md-4 col-sm-4 col-xs-6&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;Content/gdquest-game-design-portfolio-1.png&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Kiwitiki&#39;s Submarine&#34;&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-4 col-md-4 col-sm-4 col-xs-6&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;Content/gdquest-game-design-portfolio-2.png&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Kiwitiki&#39;s Submarine&#34;&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-4 col-md-4 col-sm-4 col-xs-6&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;Content/gdquest-game-design-portfolio-3.png&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Kiwitiki&#39;s Submarine&#34;&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div class=&#34;media&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;media-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&#34;max-height: 120px;&#34; class=&#34;media-object&#34; src=&#34;personal-avatar-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Nathan&#39;s avatar&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;media-body&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Hey there! &lt;small&gt;Beautiful day, isn&#39;t it?&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      I&#39;m Nathan, a courteous game designer with a taste for open source initiatives.&lt;br&gt;
      I&#39;m the author of GDquest, which stands for &lt;strong&gt;Game Design Quest&lt;/strong&gt;.
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtube.com/c/gdquest&#34; title=&#34;GDquest channel&#34;&gt;Youtube channel&lt;/a&gt; about game creation.
It is also a growing community that regroups thousands of designers.
And a company that supports open source projects!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- If you want to talk about GDquest on your website, first of all, thanks! I put up a press kit for you. It contains text, pictures and links to make it easy for you to find the information you need.

  &lt;button type=&#34;button&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-lg btn-success center-block&#34;&gt;
    Presskit
  &lt;/button&gt; --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-gdquest&#34;&gt;Why GDquest?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of learning resources available online. There are lots of entertaining and informative videos about design, tons of speed painting with commentaries… But there aren’t many places where we can find carefully designed, free education for game creation and open source technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I built Game Design Quest. I want to bring accessible, yet high quality learning resources to aspiring game designers. Game Design Quest is here to fill the gap, with a community focused mindset. Drawing inspiration from &lt;a href=&#34;https://cgcookie.com/&#34;&gt;CG Cookie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.khanacademy.org/&#34;&gt;Khan Academy&lt;/a&gt;, and Matt Kohr’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ctrlpaint.com/&#34;&gt;CtrlPaint&lt;/a&gt;, I produce resources that respects learners. I want to help people become more autonomous. To become better designers. All that following a simple, unalterable principle: &lt;strong&gt;Quality over quantity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
You don&#39;t become a professional cook by following recipes. You&#39;re a cook the day you can come up with your own recipes. The same goes with design.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On &lt;strong&gt;GDquest&lt;/strong&gt;, you&amp;rsquo;ll find:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dozens&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;https://game-design-tutorials.zeef.com/nathan.lovato&#34; title=&#34;Game Design Tutorials&#34;&gt;free game design tutorials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many Open source game assets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/GameArtQuest/&#34; title=&#34;Game Art Quest&#34;&gt;A lovely community&lt;/a&gt; of game creation enthusiasts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-8 col-sm-12&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;Meta-Dash-prototype.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Meta Dash prototype picture&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-m-not-alone&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not alone!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I collaborate with talented people around the world in my free time. In particular, I work with 3 experienced professionals on a regular basis:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arthur Shefer&lt;/strong&gt;, the author of the open source HTML5 game engine &lt;a href=&#34;http://meta2d.com/&#34;&gt;Meta2d&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MagicFred&lt;/strong&gt;, a senior 2d game artist with a unique, cute art style.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clément Brard&lt;/strong&gt;, a Unity developer and the author of &lt;a href=&#34;http://lordofthedungeon.com/&#34;&gt;Lord of the Dungeon&lt;/a&gt;, a role playing game currently in development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;More about… me! &lt;small&gt;Wait, are you sure you wanna know more?&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a French game designer; self-taught for the most part. I studied character animation and music scoring online. I make art, educational videos, &lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/gdquest&#34;&gt;soundtracks&lt;/a&gt;… I also code! Doing a bit of everything allows me to better collaborate with any teammate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For as far as I can remember, I’ve always been interested in getting in touch with people. I’ve always loved to learn new techniques and to share them with others. I had no plans to do something like GDquest 2 years ago. My goal was to make games with the same mindset as That Game Company. But I got drawn to education very naturally, for the better! At the end of the day, I’m more interested in empowering others to create than to make games as products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from GDquest, I do Chinese boxing, I study Portuguese, Japanese and… ah! I write rap songs. &lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/gdquest/souvenirs-dados&#34;&gt;Yes, for real&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Art Quest</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-6&#34; &gt;


&lt;h1&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-book
text-default
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 The training&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;free-volume-1-using-krita-as-game-artists&#34;&gt;[FREE] Volume 1 - Using Krita as game artists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;game-art-quest-free-krita-tutorials.png&#34; alt=&#34;Game Art Quest volume 1 banner - Free Krita tutorials&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This training will show you what Krita has to offer to 2d game artists. It covers the tools you need to know to work efficiently, as well as some workflow related tips.
It is &lt;strong&gt;completely free&lt;/strong&gt;, thanks to the Kickstarter backers! It will be available on both Udemy and Youtube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click the button below to learn more about the content of this training series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;volume1/&#34;&gt;&lt;button type=&#34;button&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-lg btn-default center-block&#34;&gt;
    Learn more
&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Game Art Quest has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/GameArtQuest/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-book
text-default
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 Facebook study group&lt;/a&gt;! There, we run weekly game art challenges. The goal is to become better game artists together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;volume-2-painterly-game-art-and-side-scrolling-games&#34;&gt;Volume 2 - Painterly game art and side-scrolling games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;game-art-quest-painterly.png&#34; alt=&#34;Game Art Quest volume 2 banner - painterly art&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this second training, we will take a closer look at the game creation pipeline from a game artist&amp;rsquo;s standpoint. We will create static assets for a side scrolling video game with a painterly art style, inspired by the work of VanillaWare (&lt;em&gt;Odin Sphere, Muramasa&lt;/em&gt;) and Moon Studios (&lt;em&gt;Ori and the Blind Forest&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;volume-3-cel-shaded-game-art-and-isometric-games&#34;&gt;Volume 3 - Cel shaded game art and isometric games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;game-art-quest-cel-shaded.png&#34; alt=&#34;Game Art Quest volume 3 banner - Cel shaded art&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This 3rd volume is dedicated to isometric game art. In this series, we will expand on the first 2 volumes, explore new drawing techniques as well as the characteristics of isometric games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Art Quest Discover</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/discover/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/discover/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-6&#34; &gt;

&lt;!-- DISCOVER --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;discover-game-art-quest&#34;&gt;Discover Game Art Quest!&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/vcKJibQckz4&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-you-want-to-become-a-better-2d-game-artist&#34;&gt;Do you want to become a better 2d game artist?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You came to the right place! Using &lt;strong&gt;Krita, a free and open source painting application&lt;/strong&gt;, Game Art Quest will show you both &lt;strong&gt;essential concepts&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;concrete techniques&lt;/strong&gt; professionals use on a daily basis. It is a training series in 3 volumes. The first one is &lt;strong&gt;completely free&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this series, &lt;strong&gt;I will run you through the process of creating professional grade static assets for games&lt;/strong&gt;. I will share my workflow and my productivity tricks. Not only that! I will show you how Krita is becoming a solid option for professional work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we’ll use Krita, the concepts you will learn apply to any painting application or medium. To become a more efficient game artist, you have to sharpen your observation skills and explore drawing techniques. These are the same regardless of the tools you are using, and that’s what we&amp;rsquo;re going to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;krita-screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;Nathan&#39;s picture&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The series will also cover the unique constraints we game artists face in our work. As a game artist, you have to make assets with a target resolution and camera in mind. You have to carefully draw your alpha masks. More importantly, as a game artist, &lt;strong&gt;your art has to support the gameplay: it shapes the game experience&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t know Krita yet, check out my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLhqJJNjsQ7KE3FLHIE31UgmLdcqsZfXTw&#34;&gt;19 YouTube tutorials&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to it! And &lt;a href=&#34;https://krita.org/download/krita-desktop/&#34;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; to download the application. It&amp;rsquo;s available on Windows, Linux and Mac (&lt;em&gt;port in progress&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Game Art Quest was funded &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/gdquest/game-art-quest-make-professional-2d-art-with-krita&#34;&gt;on Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt; by 424 generous backers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page is a hub for all of the activity linked to the project. Here, you will find open source game assets, the free Krita training, as well as a frequently updated roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-am-i-to-teach-you-game-art&#34;&gt;Who am I to teach you game art?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;i-am-nathan.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Nathan&#39;s picture&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m Nathan Lovato, a game designer. I the run &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtube.com/c/gdquest&#34;&gt;GDquest&lt;/a&gt; a Youtube education channel dedicated to game art and game design. Every week, I release a new tutorial. I have made dozens of tutorials already! You can find them all &lt;a href=&#34;https://game-design-tutorials.zeef.com/nathan.lovato&#34;&gt;on that page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m working &lt;strong&gt;hand in hand with the Krita developers&lt;/strong&gt;. They review my work to ensure that you get the best Krita training possible!
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Art Quest Free Assets</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/free-assets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/free-assets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-6&#34; &gt;
 &lt;!-- DISCOVER --&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-pencil
text-default
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 Open source assets&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;col-xs-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p class=&#34;text-center&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Space Adventures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
      5 electro-futuristic game soundtrack
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://gdquest.bandcamp.com/album/space-adventures&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://f1.bcbits.com/img/a3140120022_10.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Space adventures album cover&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;/&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;p class=&#34;text-center&#34;&gt;
      &lt;!-- CC 4.0 BY LICENCE --&gt;
      &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span xmlns:dct=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/terms/&#34; property=&#34;dct:title&#34;&gt;Space adventures&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a xmlns:cc=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/ns#&#34; href=&#34;gdquest.com&#34; property=&#34;cc:attributionName&#34; rel=&#34;cc:attributionURL&#34;&gt;GDquest&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;col-xs-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p class=&#34;text-center&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Open Game Art&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
      Game asset repository
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://opengameart.org/users/gdquest&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;GDquest-Freebies-Open-Source-Art-Pack-002-Xbox-Buttons.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Free Xbox buttons&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;More coming in the future!&lt;/strong&gt; In the meantime, check out my existing assets on &lt;a href=&#34;http://opengameart.org/users/gdquest&#34;&gt;OpenGameArt&lt;/a&gt;!
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Art Quest Roadmap</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/roadmap/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;!-- ROADMAP --&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-6&#34; &gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;hugoshortcode-2-roadmap-small-i-m-working-on-small&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-gears
text-default
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
Roadmap &lt;small&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m working on&amp;hellip;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan is to start with the free Krita to training series 1st as it is a prerequisite for the other 2 volumes. Then, I will move on to volume 2 to provide the Kickstarter backers with premium content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;global-progress&#34;&gt;Global progress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Volume 1&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;progress&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;progress-bar
    progress-bar-info
    progress-bar-striped
    &#34;
    role=&#34;progressbar&#34;
    aria-valuenow=&#34;15&#34; aria-valuemin=&#34;0&#34; aria-valuemax=&#34;100&#34;
    style=&#34;width: 15%;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;em&gt;The first videos are done and I finished all of my freelance contracts. I&amp;rsquo;m now working full time on the project, working on exercises, videos, and trying to help the community the best I can.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;volume-1-krita&#34;&gt;Volume 1 - Krita&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pre-production&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-check
text-success
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;progress&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;progress-bar
    progress-bar-success
    progress-bar-striped
    &#34;
    role=&#34;progressbar&#34;
    aria-valuenow=&#34;100&#34; aria-valuemin=&#34;0&#34; aria-valuemax=&#34;100&#34;
    style=&#34;width: 100%;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;em&gt;Pre-production is essential to ensure that the course will deliver its promises. In this case, the goal is to focus on game art and improving your workflow.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 0 - All you need to get started&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;progress&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;progress-bar
    progress-bar-success
    progress-bar-striped
    &#34;
    role=&#34;progressbar&#34;
    aria-valuenow=&#34;40&#34; aria-valuemin=&#34;0&#34; aria-valuemax=&#34;100&#34;
    style=&#34;width: 40%;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

This first chapter will run you through Krita&amp;rsquo;s core tools. In about 30 minutes, it will show you everything you need to know to start working on your own art!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 1 - Overview of Krita&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-check
text-success
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;progress&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;progress-bar
    progress-bar-success
    progress-bar-striped
    &#34;
    role=&#34;progressbar&#34;
    aria-valuenow=&#34;100&#34; aria-valuemin=&#34;0&#34; aria-valuemax=&#34;100&#34;
    style=&#34;width: 100%;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;em&gt;This first chapter will run you through Krita&amp;rsquo;s core tools. In about 30 minutes, it will show you everything you need to know to start working on your own art!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercises 1&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;progress&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;progress-bar
    progress-bar-info
    progress-bar-striped
    &#34;
    role=&#34;progressbar&#34;
    aria-valuenow=&#34;50&#34; aria-valuemin=&#34;0&#34; aria-valuemax=&#34;100&#34;
    style=&#34;width: 50%;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m working on exercise sheets for chapter 0 and 1, extra course material and companion video examples.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vote for Upcoming Tutorials! January 2016</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/community/vote-for-upcoming-tutorials-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 09:16:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/community/vote-for-upcoming-tutorials-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Up until now, the tutorials have been a bit random on GDquest. I jumped from theme to theme based on your requests or ideas I had. But now, we&amp;rsquo;re in 2016. I want us to try something new. &lt;strong&gt;It is time for you, members of the community, to choose the tutorial series you want to see on the channel.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose a handful of ideas based on your feedback and on what I can handle right now. There are 2 themes that I didn’t list, on purpose: animation and the Godot engine. Here&amp;rsquo;s why: there will be some animation tutorials when Krita 3.0 is released. And I am waiting for Godot 2.0 to cover it on the channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;let-your-voice-be-heard&#34;&gt;Let your voice be heard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can pick as many series as you’d like! I will produce the 3 most popular entries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gdquest.typeform.com/to/HfiMXO&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
&lt;button type=&#34;button&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-lg btn-default center-block&#34;&gt;
    Click here to Vote!
&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find more information about each and every series below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/superpowers-html5.png&#34; alt=&#34;Superpowers, the collaborative HTML5 game engine tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview-of-superpowers-the-collaborative-html5-game-engine&#34;&gt;Overview of Superpowers, the collaborative HTML5 game engine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Superpowers is a fully functional 2-D and 3-D HTML5 game editor that was released a few days ago, free and open source. It is based on three.JS and it uses Typescript, a superset of JavaScript. Not only that, it allows you to collaborate on projects online in real time! Although it is still young, the toolset is already impressive. In the development team is already at work on exciting new features!
By the way, it’s not their first shot at game engines. The project is made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://sparklinlabs.com/&#34;&gt;Sparkin Labs&lt;/a&gt;, the authors of &lt;a href=&#34;http://craftstud.io/&#34;&gt;CraftStudio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/godot-2d-engine.png&#34; alt=&#34;Human proportions, from reality to games tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview-of-godot-2-0-the-open-source-game-engine-for-2d-games&#34;&gt;Overview of Godot 2.0, the open source game engine, for 2d games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.godotengine.org/projects/godot-engine&#34;&gt;Godot&lt;/a&gt; is an open source 2d and 3d game engine. It was developed in-house by an Argentinian game studio, Okam, and released open source 2 years ago. Godot 2.0 features a robust editor with built-in animation tools, a visual shader editor, and much more!
In this series, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover the basics of 2d game development with Godot. If you want to join the community, check out its &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/godotengine/&#34;&gt;Facebook group&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/human-proportions-from-reality-to-games.png&#34; alt=&#34;Human proportions, from reality to games tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;human-proportions-from-reality-to-games&#34;&gt;Human proportions, from reality to games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of tutorials available on the basics of human anatomy and proportions (I recommend &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/user/ProkoTV&#34;&gt;Proko&amp;rsquo;s videos&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here though, I want to create a series unlike most of what you&amp;rsquo;ll find online. We will take a look at the general proportions of human beings. We will look at both male and female. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover some critical landmarks of the human body. We will then compare it with the proportions of children, and teenagers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But more importantly, we will then discuss how we can play with those proportions in games. We&amp;rsquo;ll look at what rules designers break, and which ones they respect. We will look at various examples of stylized characters in popular games, and we will then work on our own character thumbnails. It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty big topic, perfect to complement Game Art Quest!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/blender-vse.png&#34; alt=&#34;Blender VSE tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction-to-video-editing-with-blender&#34;&gt;Introduction to video editing with Blender&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blender is an impressive piece of software. It is also my open source replacement for After Effects and a video editing tool of choice. Its sequencer has its shortcomings, but it is an efficient tool to get started making videos nonetheless. In this series, I will share what I have learned creating YouTube videos with blender for the past 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/becoming-a-game-designer.png&#34; alt=&#34;Becoming a game designer tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;becoming-an-independent-game-designer&#34;&gt;Becoming an independent game designer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a game designer? How can you become a professional or an independent game designer? Based on my experience creating games with a talented engineer, working as a freelancer and now creating Game Design Quest, I will share what I learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t tell you which college you should pick, but I can help you to teach yourself game design. That is what this series is all about. &lt;strong&gt;It is not a series about creating a business and selling your games!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/introduction-music-scoring-for-games.png&#34; alt=&#34;Introduction to music scoring for games tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-primer-on-music-scoring-for-games&#34;&gt;A primer on music scoring for games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, but I write and produce &lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/gdquest&#34;&gt;game soundtracks&lt;/a&gt;! I actually studied music scoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing good music takes a lot of experience! And the resources for it are sometimes overly complicated, or plain mystical. I was lucky to learn music with a teacher who’s all about analysis and clarity. I&amp;rsquo;d like to share some of what he taught me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/243108339&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This isn’t a series about music production using a DAW&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Digital Audio Workstation&lt;/em&gt;) like FL studio. Music scoring is a huge topic. This is but an introduction to music as a language! I will try to give you a good sense of what the building blocks of a score are, and what scoring for games is like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/rock-and-grass-tiles.png&#34; alt=&#34;Rock tiles tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;painting-rock-and-grass-tiles-for-2d-games&#34;&gt;Painting rock and grass tiles for 2d games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one type of 2-D game asset that is rarely explained online: tiles. These are sprites that connect seamlessly to one another and that you can reuse extensively to create your game backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial series, I will show you how to create tiles for the ground and for walls or hanging ceiling in an outdoor environment, in a side scrolling game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/kickstarter-tips.png&#34; alt=&#34;Game Art Quest Kickstarter tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;kickstarter-all-of-my-hard-learned-tips&#34;&gt;Kickstarter: all of my hard learned tips!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you know I ran a Kickstarter campaign that was successfully funded. Better than that, it doubled the initial goal! During those hectic weeks, struggling to keep up with the frightening workload, I learned a lot about crowdfunding. With this theme, I want to go over the preparation, the ongoing production and the communication you have to take care of during the course of a Kickstarter campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phaser auto completion in Atom</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/programming/phaser-auto-completion-in-atom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/programming/phaser-auto-completion-in-atom/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This little guide will show you how to use the tern-phaser plugin by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/angelozerr&#34;&gt;Angelo&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;http://atom.io&#34;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;installing-tern:f84bfcbc5e082e525c63bea486a45c9e&#34;&gt;Installing tern&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first part explains how to get npm, install tern and the tern-phaser plugin. The first thing that you need to ensure is that you have Node.js installed on your computer. You can download it on &lt;a href=&#34;https://nodejs.org/en/&#34;&gt;https://nodejs.org/en/&lt;/a&gt;. This will give you access to npm as well, a handy package manager for js libraries and plugins. It allows you to download install all sorts of packages from the command prompt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once Node.js has finished installing, we have a few commands to call from the command prompt. On windows, you can access the command line need to press the Windows R key combination, type &amp;#8220;cmd&amp;#8221; and press enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/HVB8KRn.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;463&#34; height=&#34;247&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we need to install a few packages. First, there is tern, the JS analyzer that the tern-phaser plugin uses. In the command line tool, type &amp;#8220;npm install tern&amp;#8221; and press enter. Npm will take care of the install for you, it will just take a moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/H1xIdew.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;465&#34; height=&#34;247&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then need the tern-phaser plugin to be installed where the tern package has been put. You can let windows find the folder for you by typing &amp;#8220;npm install -g tern-phaser&amp;#8221; in the command prompt and pressing enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/qqUNi8c.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;657&#34; height=&#34;196&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-manual-route:f84bfcbc5e082e525c63bea486a45c9e&#34;&gt;The manual route&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If the automatic install of tern-phaser doesn&amp;#8217;t work&lt;/strong&gt;, you&amp;#8217;ll have to go navigate to the tern install folder manually from the command prompt. To change the folder the command prompt is in, you need to type cd (&lt;em&gt;current directory&lt;/em&gt;) followed by the path you want to reach. By default, tern should be installed to C:\Users**YourName**\AppData\Roaming\npm\node_modules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the command prompt, you then have to enter &amp;#8220;cd C:\Users**YourName**\AppData\Roaming\npm\node_modules&amp;#8221;. Note that you can copy the path from windows and paste it in the command prompt using the right mouse button (&lt;em&gt;Ctrl V doesn&amp;#8217;t work by default&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/4shbnrB.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;487&#34; height=&#34;174&#34; /&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;thumbnail wp-caption alignnone&#34; style=&#34;width: 298px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/rX9oAKb.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;298&#34; height=&#34;217&#34; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;Right click on the command line tool to paste text.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you got to the right folder, just type npm &amp;#8220;install tern-phaser&amp;#8221; and press enter.&lt;figure class=&#34;thumbnail wp-caption alignnone&#34; style=&#34;width: 677px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/zJusEnO.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;677&#34; height=&#34;115&#34; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;Without -g, the command installs the tern-phaser package in the folder you&amp;#8217;re currently in.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;using-tern-phaser-with-atom:f84bfcbc5e082e525c63bea486a45c9e&#34;&gt;Using tern-phaser with Atom&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, you have both tern and tern-phaser installed on your computer. Let&amp;#8217;s move to setting up atom to work with tern. There is no native integration of tern in atom. However, there is a plugin called &lt;strong&gt;atom-ternjs&lt;/strong&gt; that works like a charm. We can install the package from the command line as well. Either &lt;strong&gt;close and reopen the command&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;prompt&lt;/strong&gt; or navigate back to your root folder with the following command: &amp;#8220;cd C:\Users\YourName&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, to call the Atom Package Manager, you need to use the apm command. Type &amp;#8220;apm install atom-ternjs&amp;#8221; and press enter. This will add this package to atom for you. To use tern with your project, you just need to have a tern configuration file. Atom-ternjs can create a basic config file for you. In Atom, you first need to have at least one javascript file loaded. Then, go to packages -&amp;gt; Atom ternjs -&amp;gt; Configure project&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/QjFJpud.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;334&#34; height=&#34;189&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can set some parameters in the newly opened tab and click on save and restart server. This will create a new .tern-project file in your project folder. We still need to tell it to use the phaser plugin. You just have to add &amp;#8220;phaser&amp;#8221; in the plugins section. Here&amp;#8217;s the content of my .tern-project file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;kt-simple-box&#34; style=&#34;background-color:rgba(255, 255, 255, 1); min-height:1px; padding-top:20px; padding-bottom:20px; padding-left:20px; padding-right:20px; &#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    {   &amp;#8220;ecmaVersion&amp;#8221;: 5,   &amp;#8220;libs&amp;#8221;: [&amp;#8220;browser&amp;#8221;],   &amp;#8220;plugins&amp;#8221;: {     &amp;#8220;phaser&amp;#8221;: {}   } }
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/EC06Yl4.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;467&#34; height=&#34;237&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save your file, and then go to package -&amp;gt; Atom Ternjs -&amp;gt; Restart server. If you don&amp;#8217;t get any error, you&amp;#8217;re good to go! &lt;em&gt;Note that having a phaser.js file next to your .tern-project file can prevent tern-phaser from working &amp;#8211; in which case you&amp;#8217;ll get a series of errors in Atom&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/Fd9QqM3.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;844&#34; height=&#34;403&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homepage</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-to-game-design-quest&#34;&gt;Welcome to Game Design Quest!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;media&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;media-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#34;media-object&#34; src=&#34;http://www.gravatar.com/avatar/926e28d2acbb403710576711d0fc93a8?s=80&#34; alt=&#34;Nathan&#39;s avatar&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;media-body&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      I&#39;m Nathan, a professional game designer.
      I&#39;m the author of &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtube.com/c/gdquest&#34;&gt;GDquest&lt;/a&gt;, a Youtube channel filled with tutorials about game art and game design.
      And I&#39;m building a community around &lt;strong&gt;game creation&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;open source software&lt;/strong&gt;.

      The website will be a hub for the community and open source assets.
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

It is a &lt;strong&gt;Work in Progress&lt;/strong&gt;! If you want to help with the design or to report an error, please tell me on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/NathanGDquest&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or via &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:nathan.lovato.art@gmail.com&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;!


&lt;!-- This website is a hub for all of the activity around GDquest. Here, you&#39;ll find links to dozens of tutorials, open source game assets and a roadmap for future content. --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;highlighted-video&#34;&gt;Highlighted video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/uGiucAklXXc&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homepage</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/roadmap/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;in-the-making:cd4a1b36ed2b93cfc52abf77a7d25d03&#34;&gt;In the making&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GDquest website, v0.2&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;progress&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;progress-bar
    progress-bar-info
    progress-bar-striped
    &#34;
    role=&#34;progressbar&#34;
    aria-valuenow=&#34;40&#34; aria-valuemin=&#34;0&#34; aria-valuemax=&#34;100&#34;
    style=&#34;width: 40%;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tasks:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple system to generate course pages. &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-check
text-success
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data-driven author widgets &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-check
text-success
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refine the Game Art Quest page

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve course page for Kickstarter backers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add open source assets and finish vol.1 course notes. &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-check
text-success
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analytics support &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-check
text-success
&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tutorials: Game Art Quest - Volume 1&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;progress&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;progress-bar
    progress-bar-success
    progress-bar-striped
    &#34;
    role=&#34;progressbar&#34;
    aria-valuenow=&#34;15&#34; aria-valuemin=&#34;0&#34; aria-valuemax=&#34;100&#34;
    style=&#34;width: 15%;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m working full time on 3 training series dedicated to &lt;a href=&#34;https://krita.org/&#34;&gt;Krita&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>