<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GDquest</title>
    <link>http://gdquest.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on GDquest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://gdquest.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Krita brushes for game artists</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/krita-brushes-for-game-artists</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/krita-brushes-for-game-artists</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Version 10 (&lt;em&gt;January 2017&lt;/em&gt;) contains:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;61 unique brush presets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 pdf documents&lt;/strong&gt; to help you get started with the brushes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monthly updates&lt;/strong&gt;. More brushes and videos are already on your way!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The premium tier adds:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More than 30 minutes of exclusive video tutorials&lt;/strong&gt; to get the most out of the brushes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;natural media brushkit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Priority support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take my time to design the presets and ensure that they are worth adding to the pack. I also use them in my daily work to ensure that they are tested thoroughly in all kinds of configurations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-other-artists-have-to-say&#34;&gt;What other artists have to say&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/page/krita-brushes/testimonial-zhillustrator.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Thumbnails painted with Krita by Živko Kondić&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/zhille&#34;&gt;Zhillustrator&lt;/a&gt; writes: &amp;laquo;Nathan&amp;rsquo;s brush set has some essential brushes for digital painting that will ease your way into Krita&amp;rsquo;s powerful brush engine. My favorites in the pack are the mix and smudge brushes. Honestly, if you like the Lite set, it&amp;rsquo;s worth it, Krita is going somewhere.&amp;raquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See more of Zhillustrator&amp;rsquo;s work &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artstation.com/artist/zhille&#34;&gt;on Artstation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gum.co/krita-brushes-gdquest-lite&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/page/krita-brushes/krita-brushes-banner-lite.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Krita brushes banner lite&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;free-krita-brushes&#34;&gt;Free Krita brushes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part? There is actually a free, smaller version of this set, so you can try it out for yourself.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gumroad.com/l/krita-brushes-gdquest-lite&#34;&gt;Click here to download the free Krita brushes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;changelog&#34;&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;version-10-january-2017&#34;&gt;Version 10 - January 2017&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version 10 is a maintenance update. It comes with 4 new presets, but also 11 existing brushes got better! Performance improvements, improved feel&amp;hellip; a good way to prepare major changes coming over the next few updates. As on every other month, I released &lt;a href=&#34;https://gumroad.com/l/krita-brushes-gdquest-lite&#34;&gt;7 new free Krita brushes&lt;/a&gt; in the.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;new-brushes&#34;&gt;New brushes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paint Flat Softer: Softer version of the flat paintbrush&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paint Flat Sharper: Sharper version of the flat paintbrush, but 40% slower to render&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Airbrush Shading: An airbrush taylored to block shadows in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Airbrush Softer: A subtle airbrush, extra smooth compared to the base Gdquest Airbrush&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;improved-brushes&#34;&gt;Improved brushes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blend Flat: pen rotation support, improved tip and blend curve, new size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blend Smoky: improved blend curver, new size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blend Smudge: improved opacity curve, new size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud Builder: new size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud Builder Soft: new size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fill Flat Directional: improved for outlines and inking, new size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ink Brush: improved pressure curve to make lower sizes more accessible, new size. Feels more like a Japanese Ink Brush&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ink Rough: improved opacity curve, new opacity, new size. Feels more like an alcohol marker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ink Sketch: new size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paint Flat: 2x faster, pen rotation support, sharper short edge on the brush tip, softer long edge, improved blend curve, new size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paint Round Dry: 25% faster, improved pressure and color blend curves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;version-9-dec-2016&#34;&gt;Version 9 - Dec 2016&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 new presets including a blur tool, splatter brushes, and a rock texture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 natural media presets, and especially a powerful cloud painting tool (premium)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a new tutorial on cloud painting (premium)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;version-8-nov-2016&#34;&gt;Version 8 - Nov 2016&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 textured rock brushes: these presets will allow you to add 2 types of sharp grain to your rocks, for a more believable look.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smear cloud: whether you want to slightly blur or completely diffuse your edges, this is a very efficient preset to do so. It blurs your painting fast and provides very good control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smoke dusty: this brush can be used for both clouds and smoke. Unlike the existing cloud builder brushes, it offers some high frequency details for a richer look.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 water brushes: the first water brushes are in! They&amp;rsquo;re useful to paint waves, for a lake, a sea or an ocean.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tree leaves builder: a nice brush to quickly add detailed leaves to a piece of concept art.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;version-7-oct-2016&#34;&gt;Version 7 (Oct 2016)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Rock presets: draw small, round and stylized rocks with Rock builder stylized, and detail them with the Rock_detail brush&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 special presets for shading: the special_shadow brush allows you to stamp simple round shadows, to place under characters and small assets. The other 2 brushes are directional shading brushes, with a sharp and a soft side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 pencil-looking brushes: one for sketching, and one for shading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated paint_old preset: I remade the preset from scratch. It is at least twice as fast, and strokes are more consistent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;version-6-sep-2016&#34;&gt;Version 6 (Sep 2016)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 pixel art deform tools: pixel art-friendly Grow, Shrink, Move and Swirl tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cloud builder brushes: the first builders are here! These presets will help you paint accurate sprite silhouettes in no time. These will work for both stylized and realistic clouds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 smoke brushes: for when you need to achieve a textured smoky effect. Also useful to add definition to materials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text-based install guide (pdf)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An intro to brush families (pdf)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the full release changelog, check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gumroad.com/l/krita-brushes-for-game-artists&#34;&gt;Gumroad page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the office - January news</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/news/2017/in-the-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 17:35:09 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/news/2017/in-the-office/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/aouow3pfa7Q&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The past 2 months have been hectic. I’ll pass on the details, but since a few days, I’m renting an office. After so much time struggling to work from home, you can’t imagine how great it feels! I not only have access to the room 24/7, it’s also part of a local business incubator. The structure offer a lot of support, free training on accounting, management, legal stuff… All of which is quite complex in France. The building is great, and there are other entrepreneurs to share your thoughts and struggles with. Actually, the team in the office right in front of mine is into 3-D printing, and they are super nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, it’s news time. In this month’s update, we talk about the weekly releases on the premium game art tutorial, the Godot tutorial series that’s happening right now on the channel, and FOSDEM and GodotCon, 2 events taking place from February 4 to 7. I’m going to give the Godot team a hand and prepare some upcoming project, so we can meet there! To get more details about all of that, I invite you to watch the video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you in February for the next update!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back from japan, back to work</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/news/2016/back-from-japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 20:16:29 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/news/2016/back-from-japan/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I’m back from Japan! Physically at least: my heart is still back there. I’ve been traveling around the country for a bit less than a month, and the experience was incredible. It was a great occasion to practice Japanese and get a better sense for the culture. I’ve read and been told a lot of things before going, and reality felt a lot subtler than what you would expect at first. Some facts were somewhat true, others plain wrong. The collectivism there felt wonderful. The french culture is a lot more individualistic, which is part of what makes me feel like a foreigner here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be a sheer contrast between Japanese people&amp;rsquo;s behavior during daytime, and at night. When they are tipsy, or even completely drunk, you&amp;rsquo;re up for all sorts of surprises! And it&amp;rsquo;s fine for them to drink way too much and end up sleeping on the sidewalk in larger cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, Japan is beautiful. And a picture is probably worth a thousand words in that regards:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/144749747@N03/30581295540/in/album-72157674849188902/&#34; title=&#34;Sunset on Naoshima&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/6/5783/30581295540_8642c0298a_b.jpg&#34; width=&#34;1024&#34; height=&#34;576&#34; alt=&#34;Sunset on Naoshima&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve mostly been out hiking, meeting people, making friends&amp;hellip; enjoying the soothing nature. If you ever travel there, I would warmly recommend walking the Kumano Kodo, a pilgrimage route. At least if you’re into trekking. Oh, and when you&amp;rsquo;re on your way down to Tanabe City, be sure stop by Osaka and eat some freshly cooked okonomiyaki with cheese topping. It tastes great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-for-a-proper-workplace&#34;&gt;Looking for a proper workplace&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, let’s get back to the channel. Last week, I wrote a business plan and applied to a local business incubator. It’s a place where you can get an office, along with other young companies. Experienced people follow your work and are here to guide you. If they accept GDquest, this will help the project greatly in the coming year. It is getting hard for me to work at home. I need to get out of here. That’s why I took a few extra days to refine the document: I want - no, I need it to work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;upcoming-updates&#34;&gt;Upcoming updates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about what&amp;rsquo;s coming next on GDquest. As far as free content is concerned, until the end of December, you’ll be getting some more Krita tutorials from the Game Art Quest series. In the meantime, I’ll be hard at work on a few things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next training product, which is very important, the game art workshop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Krita brushes and the Krita training series will get a little bit of love through monthly updates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I must improve some aspects of the website. In particular, a library page is coming in the next few weeks. It will compile all of the tutorials from the channel in an appealing and organized way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;And there will still be weekly free videos on the channel. I have to produce some new ones, in parallel to the training products. I&amp;rsquo;ve already prepared the next free series, which will be an introduction to the Godot game engine!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And hopefully we&amp;rsquo;ll find some time to do a few collabs with other artists. We got in touch with Daniel, aka &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCGgpthBWDbFX2GSljMw-MdQ&#34;&gt;Borodante&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;pronounced Borrrrr-rodante&lt;/em&gt;), and some other tutorial makers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;come-chat-with-the-community-on-discord&#34;&gt;Come chat with the community on Discord!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;card-box clearfix&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;card-content&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I’ve opened a server on Discord for everyone in the community to join and talk about game creation with open source programs.
      Whether you just want to drop by and say hi, showcase your artwork or share your knowledge about Krita and Godot, you’re
      more than welcome!
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p class=&#34;text--center&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/KVaCsSP&#34; class=&#34;button button--pill button--success button--full lead&#34;&gt;Join the Discord server&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sara-tepes&#34;&gt;Sara Tepes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sara Tepes, a hard-working 17 years old illustrator, talked about GDquest in her last video. I’ve been following her for months now, and her message was heartwarming! So now it’s my turn: if you want to see appealing live Krita demonstrations, check out Sara’s channel on YouTube. She uploads commented time-lapses every week and she already produces very appealing art despite her young age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCWgMcluGLnaVpCWmscaFs_Q&#34;&gt;Sara Tepes on Youtube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;360&#34; style=&#34;max-width:100%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/orgVs2csqbo&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;that-said&#34;&gt;That said&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time to get back to work! I&amp;rsquo;ll upload the Krita brushes update in the coming week (Nov 14-20), as well as a video overview of the new features in Krita 3.1. Yes, a new major release is right around the corner, and among other things, it&amp;rsquo;s going to be the first stable Mac version!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your time!
Nathan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: If you want to see more shots I took in Japan, click on the picture below. It&amp;rsquo;ll take you to the album on Flickr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/144749747@N03/30766469012/in/dateposted-public/&#34; title=&#34;highlights (40 of 44)&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/6/5546/30766469012_1a163667d6_b.jpg&#34; width=&#34;1024&#34; height=&#34;576&#34; alt=&#34;highlights (40 of 44)&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Art Quest vol1 done! Off to Japan</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/news/2016/japan-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 08:24:05 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/news/2016/japan-news/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Yes, the first volume of Game Art Quest is done. 6.2 hours of free Krita tutorials (some are still upcoming on the channel). 7 hours if you include the first bonus series of the year: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLhqJJNjsQ7KExm_EYLVhD6yf4Afax24fV&#34;&gt;Introduction to monster design for 2-D games&lt;/a&gt;. Looking back at the Kickstarter description, this is already more than the promised as far as the total length is concerned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gum.co/krita-tutorial-for-game-artists&#34;&gt;Early access&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i class=&#34;my-fa fa-shopping-cart
text--success
 text--inherit&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/volume-1/krita-tutorial-for-game-artists&#34;&gt;Available tutorials&lt;/a&gt; (free)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The extra premium brushes and their companion tutorials are also getting pretty big. With this month&amp;rsquo;s update, it now includes 34 presets and more than 30 minutes of video tutorials. And more coming monthly.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/Aq3LvQYyld4&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;But we are not done yet! I&amp;rsquo;m pre-producing the 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; volume of Game Art Quest, which will help you to put all you&amp;rsquo;ve learned in practice. It is a workshop series in which you&amp;rsquo;ll create your own game mockups. On top of that, I&amp;rsquo;m planning to update the first volume from time to time with assignments and useful documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, for now, it&amp;rsquo;s time to take some rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;off-to-japan&#34;&gt;Off to Japan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m taking a flight to Japan on October 3, and coming back at the end of the month. It&amp;rsquo;s a trip I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking forward to for a long time. And now more than ever, after 2 years studying Japanese, with already a number of people to meet there. I&amp;rsquo;ll have both a camera and a tablet to share the most interesting adventures with you on social networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gamedev-wise, I&amp;rsquo;ll be paying the author of Pico8 and Voxatron a visit at his picotachi café in Tokyo, along with a French indie developer who lives in Japan, Erhune, the co-author of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gangsofspace.com/&#34;&gt;Gangs of Space&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m also meeting a tech developer from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.q-games.com/&#34;&gt;Q-games&lt;/a&gt; in Kyoto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from that, I&amp;rsquo;ll travel to the sacred Shinto island of Miyajima, walk the Kumano Kodo, the emperors&amp;rsquo; pilgrimage route, meet Japanese monkeys in Kyoto, and a lot more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I am not gone yet, and there&amp;rsquo;s still some more content coming your way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-krita-brushes&#34;&gt;More Krita brushes!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest version of the Krita brushes for game artists is out. The full set now contains 34 presets, 5 video tutorials and 2 PDF guides. It includes pixel art drawing tools, but more importantly the first few presets of the elements family, which are dedicated to help you paint elements of nature efficiently and flexibly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gum.co/krita-brushes-for-game-artists&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/page/krita-brushes/Krita brushes banner 2016-07.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Krita brushes for game artists&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2 cloud builder brushes in this release make it effortless to paint game-ready clouds sprites. Using the cloud blender from last month, you can also soften any sharp edge with great control. Even though I&amp;rsquo;m away next month, you&amp;rsquo;ll still get your dose of new tools!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lite set also got some love. It is now twice as big, for a total of 16 presets. It is completely free, and gets an update every 2 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gum.co/krita-brushes-for-game-artists&#34;&gt;Krita brushes premium&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i class=&#34;my-fa fa-shopping-cart
text--success
 text--inherit&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gumroad.com/l/krita-brushes-gdquest-lite&#34;&gt;Lite version&lt;/a&gt; (free)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;plans-for-the-week&#34;&gt;Plans for the week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is not enough time to start producing and releasing the new training this week. I&amp;rsquo;d rather take the time to pre-produce it the right way, and be ready to create the first tutorials when I&amp;rsquo;m back from Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that, I have some overdue editing jobs for the KDE community. I interviewed experienced open source developers back in June, and they had some deep insights to share with people interested in free technologies. That&amp;rsquo;s something I have to tackle this week. The videos will come out as a bonus during October.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This transitional week is also a good occasion to work on the website. A new version recently rolled out with some improvements, especially simplified visuals. There&amp;rsquo;s less useless content, so that the current 200 to 300 daily visitors get a better experience with navigation. Especially newcomers. Here are the goals for the week:
- Update the main Krita training page
- Improve the course page&amp;rsquo;s visuals for clearer navigation
- Add accessibility-related code
- And maybe add an about page again&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, I&amp;rsquo;ve got to prepare posts for social networks in advance so you still get your weekly tutorials and some useful tips next month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, that&amp;rsquo;s it for now. If you have to remember one thing from this post: I&amp;rsquo;m away in October. So don&amp;rsquo;t expect superfast replies to emails and questions. Oh, and by the way, the channel got past 1 million views. Next stop: the 10 million mark!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Update</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/news/2016/summer-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 13:49:48 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/news/2016/summer-news/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It has been a while since the last behind the scenes news post. There&amp;rsquo;s been good progress with the tutorials and the brushes. I&amp;rsquo;ve been hard at work lately, especially changing my workflow to increase production speed, maintaining the same quality. On the other hand, I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to update the website and social networks as often as I would&amp;rsquo;ve liked. Aside from that&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;krita-3-0-1-is-out&#34;&gt;Krita 3.0.1 is out!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krita 3.0 .1 came out this week. Although it was just a minor bug-fixing release, it does add a number of new features to the program. These include soft proofing, mirror tool options, horizontal and vertical flip buttons in free transform mode, threshold and wavelet decompose, the ability to use the gradient map as a filter layer, and more! You can find the full release notes &lt;a href=&#34;https://krita.org/en/item/krita-3-0-1-update-brings-numerous-fixes/&#34;&gt;on&lt;/a&gt; the official website, and below is a video overview of most of these:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/9S_x6koOVBo&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also an &lt;a href=&#34;https://krita.org/en/item/experimental-osx-build-available/&#34;&gt;experimental Mac build&lt;/a&gt; with openGL support! It needs extensive testing, so if you&amp;rsquo;re a Mac user, it&amp;rsquo;s time to get your hands dirty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-swiss-game-academy&#34;&gt;The Swiss Game Academy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In August, I was invited to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gameacademy.ch/&#34;&gt;Swiss Game Academy&lt;/a&gt;, a weeklong event where Swiss game developers team up to offer a very affordable training to students interested in game creation. At the same time, it is a game jam open to enthusiasts of any age, starting at 10! Although I&amp;rsquo;m French, I live next to the Swiss border, and I got in touch with developers last year. There are few game studios in the country, yet the indie scene is really lively. Many jams take place around the Geneva lake, and dozens of people meet monthly in Lausanne to share insights about their projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- TODO: Screenshot --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the Game Academy, we were a team of 15 people to take care of dozens of students, and we took turns to train them in the morning. I was there to show how to create game sprites with Krita, and to hopefully convince hobbyists that they didn&amp;rsquo;t need Photoshop! Few of them had ever heard of the program, and most were quite impressed with its features, including other members of the staff. The wraparound mode, symmetry drawing tools, the pop-up palette, and more importantly PSD support seduced many. Over the course of 3 hours, we covered all of the fundamentals, and went through the whole asset creation workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the last event I accepted to be part of, and that until the whole Kickstarter project is done. It was great though!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ludum-dare-36-small-learning-godot-preparing-the-next-series-small&#34;&gt;Ludum Dare 36 &lt;small&gt;learning Godot, preparing the next series&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming back from Switzerland, there was the 36&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; edition of the Ludum Dare. I took this opportunity to prepare the next training series for Game Art Quest: the one where we&amp;rsquo;ll focus on creating games sprites. I made a very small game that showcases what you can do with static game assets. The project is set in the world of David Revoy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.peppercarrot.com/&#34;&gt;Pepper and Carrot&lt;/a&gt;, with our favorite ginger cat as the main character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a small isometric 2-D game where a cat throws ridiculous spells at scarecrows and ghosts. Alright, I&amp;rsquo;ll figure out a nicer introduction for the course release! At that occasion, I learned how to work with Godot 2.1, which deeply impressed me. It came a long way since version 1.0. It feels a lot more polished, and it&amp;rsquo;s well documented. Within 3 days, I managed to get a small working prototype. There&amp;rsquo;s work left to polish it a bit, but it&amp;rsquo;ll give us a nice base project for the game art workshops, where I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to replace my sprites and put your own art into the game!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2016/09/ludum-dare-36-godot-prototype.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Carrot&#39;s Magic: my Ludum Dare 36 prototype&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;krita-tutorials-where-are-we-at&#34;&gt;Krita tutorials: where are we at?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve passed the halfway mark! You now have more than 6 hours of tutorials available &lt;a href=&#34;https://gum.co/krita-tutorial-for-game-artists&#34;&gt;on Gumroad&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;if you backed the initial Kickstarter, you got a coupon via email&lt;/em&gt;). There&amp;rsquo;s one chapter left in the first volume, dedicated to Krita&amp;rsquo;s animation features. I know that a lot of you are waiting eagerly for this series, and it&amp;rsquo;s around the corner!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- TODO: Screenshot --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Game Art Quest doesn&amp;rsquo;t end there. After that, I will focus on the game art workshops, in which we will explore 2 different art styles: painterly, and cel shaded. At the same time, we will learn more about the constraints we face with camera angles as 2-D game artists. Exploring side-scrolling and isometric games will be a great occasion to talk about how we can achieve good atmospheric perspective and decent character proportions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will do my best to provide you as much information as possible on the topics. Contrary to the first volume though, it has to be a real workshop. You&amp;rsquo;ll get to create your own sprites along with the videos, and if you do all of the assignments, you&amp;rsquo;ll end up with your own game mockup at the end. This workshop series will take me a few more months to create, especially as I&amp;rsquo;m flying off to Japan in October (holidays!). And you can expect this second series to be about 5 hours long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you want to know when it&amp;rsquo;ll be available? You just have to enter your email address in the field below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.gumroad-follow-form-embed button,.gumroad-follow-form-embed input{font-size:15px;font-family:-apple-system,&#34;.SFNSDisplay-Regular&#34;,&#34;Helvetica Neue&#34;,Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;height:40px!important}.gumroad-follow-form-embed{zoom:1}.gumroad-follow-form-embed:after,.gumroad-follow-form-embed:before{display:table;line-height:0;content:&#34;&#34;}.gumroad-follow-form-embed:after{clear:both}.gumroad-follow-form-embed *{margin:0;border:0;padding:0;outline:0;box-sizing:border-box!important;float:left!important}.gumroad-follow-form-embed input{border-radius:4px 0 0 4px;line-height:20px;background:top right no-repeat #fff;border:1px solid #ddd;border-right:0;color:#aaa;padding:10px;box-shadow:inset 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,.02);text-rendering:optimizeLegibility;font-smoothing:antialiased;-webkit-appearance:none;-moz-appearance:caret;width:65%!important}.gumroad-follow-form-embed button{border-radius:0 4px 4px 0;box-shadow:0 1px 1px rgba(0,0,0,.12);-webkit-transition:all .05s ease-in-out;transition:all .05s ease-in-out;display:inline-block;padding:11px 15px 12px;cursor:pointer;color:#fff;line-height:100%;border:1px solid #31989d;filter:&#34;progid:DXImageTransform.Microsoft.gradient(startColorstr=#5ccfd4, endColorstr=#329ca1, GradientType=0)&#34;;background:-webkit-linear-gradient(top,#5ccfd4,#329ca1);background:linear-gradient(to bottom,#5ccfd4,#329ca1);width:35%!important}&lt;/style&gt;&lt;form action=&#34;https://gumroad.com/follow_from_embed_form&#34; class=&#34;form gumroad-follow-form-embed&#34; method=&#34;post&#34;&gt;&lt;input name=&#34;seller_id&#34; type=&#34;hidden&#34; value=&#34;6873367754130&#34;&gt; &lt;input name=&#34;email&#34; placeholder=&#34;Your email address&#34; type=&#34;email&#34;&gt; &lt;button data-custom-highlight-color=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;submit&#34;&gt;Sign up&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/form&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;off-to-japan&#34;&gt;Off to Japan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I&amp;rsquo;m flying off to Japan in October. After 2 years studying the language, it is time to go and discover the country. I&amp;rsquo;ll be spending some time in large cities, as well as in nature. I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to walking on the Kumano Kodo, a network of mountain trails where emperors used to do pilgrimages. I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to share nice pictures and my experiences in this intriguing county. I will also be meeting some game developers and hopefully the Krita artist &lt;a href=&#34;https://krita.org/en/item/interview-with-omiya-tou/&#34;&gt;Omiya Tou&lt;/a&gt; in Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- TODO: Screenshot --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have travelled very little so far, and it&amp;rsquo;ll be my first time on a long-haul flight. It&amp;rsquo;s also a personal treat after a few years working in the gaming industry, taking little time off, and creating GDquest 18 months ago. It&amp;rsquo;ll be a great occasion to fully relax, and come back to full productivity in November.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, it&amp;rsquo;s time to get back to work. Well, actually to share dinner with a few friends, at the time of writing. But you know what I mean!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June update: the Randa meetings</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/news/2016/kickstarter-news-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 11:17:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/news/2016/kickstarter-news-june/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re getting to the end of June. It&amp;rsquo;s time to sum up all that&amp;rsquo;s been happening this month. The short version: I kept improving the website, went to the biggest yearly KDE development sprint in Randa, Switzerland, and added about 1h of tutorials dedicated to Krita 3&amp;rsquo;s new features in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/volume-1/krita-tutorial-for-game-artists&#34;&gt;Krita training&lt;/a&gt;. You can find more details about what happened in Randa, and what the plans are for July, below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;randa&#34;&gt;Randa&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From June 13 to 19, I was in Randa, KDE&amp;rsquo;s biggest yearly sprint. KDE is a large community of free software developers and users. Krita is part of it, and it&amp;rsquo;s certainly the most popular multiplatform KDE program today. Sadly, no one else from the team could make it to the sprint this year. They ran a hectic Kickstarter in May, and boud, Krita&amp;rsquo;s maintainer, had too much work to do the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Randa was an amazing experience for me. There, I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to produce Krita tutorials. I mostly jumped around projects, learned about the whole KDE ecosystem, and helped with communication and UX design. It&amp;rsquo;s incredible to get in touch with so many cultures at once. People came from all around the world. There was Joseph, from Kenya, who came to port KDEnlive on Windows. Lays and Ayrton, from Brazil, working on an open 3d printing program. Developers from India, Germany, Denmark&amp;hellip; you name it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2016/06/Randa-meetings-work-discussions.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;KDE Randa meetings: developers discussions&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All those people are so different&amp;hellip; and yet they all work together to hopefully make the computer world a slightly better place. There was such a strong ambience there that we all worked very hard. I was up around 7:00 every morning, and went off to bed at 23:00. I spent the vast majority of the day working. And it was pretty much the same for everybody else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The village we stayed at itself was peaceful and lovely. A perfect, undistracted place to both focus and relax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2016/06/Randa-view-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Randa view of the mountains&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The view was gorgeous from my office&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;time-to-make-some-money-again&#34;&gt;Time to make some money again&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I told you in a previous update, Game Art Quest became bigger than what it was supposed to be. With the Kickstarter, we raised enough money for six months of full-time work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These six months are getting to an end, so I have to make a bit of money again. I&amp;rsquo;m getting new offers on a weekly basis, but until now, I almost declined them all. However, I accepted one job writing Krita tutorials for a magazine this month. It is a great opportunity as they asked me to work on animation, which I haven&amp;rsquo;t covered yet in the training, thus it&amp;rsquo;s not distracting me from daily work too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking to start working on and selling the next 2 volumes of the training in early access at the end of July. If I sell enough, I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to keep working full-time on it. Otherwise, I&amp;rsquo;ll dedicate one day per week to client work, which shouldn&amp;rsquo;t slow down the production of the training noticeably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-video-a-week&#34;&gt;One video a week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s summer time in here. The hot weather is back, and people are taking time off. I&amp;rsquo;m not! I&amp;rsquo;ll be here all summer long, working at the same pace. However, now that the tutorial series covering Krita 3&amp;rsquo;s new features is out, we&amp;rsquo;re going to move back to a rhythm of 1 tutorial per week on the channel. This will give me more time to improve the GDquest Blender add-on, and to prepare the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/post/community/vote-for-upcoming-tutorials-january-2016/&#34;&gt;future series&lt;/a&gt; coming to the channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-week&#34;&gt;This week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To wrap up June, I have to release a brush pack update. This new version will contain 4 new brushes, and I painted a new thumbnail for the blender brush, as the current one looks horrible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2016/06/Flat-blender-brush.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;New flat blender brush icon&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I&amp;rsquo;m working on the fourth chapter in the Krita training, to release it as soon as possible. It will introduce you to the game assets creation workflow. As soon as it is out, I will move on to the second volume of the training, which you will be able to access on Gumroad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving into July, I have to get working again on the blender of VSE add-on. It is one of the main ways I can improve my productivity creating the video tutorials now. My goal is to add one new feature every single week, even if it&amp;rsquo;s small. This week for instance, I&amp;rsquo;m working on an import feature that loads all of the project&amp;rsquo;s video and audio files to the VSE in one click. As I get to create up to six videos in a single week, this feature will be a real time saver. And with that, I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to release the first public version of the add-on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2016/06/blender-vse-add-on-code.png&#34; alt=&#34;Blender GDquest VSE add-on import code&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The import code is already there - it just needs to be refined&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, it&amp;rsquo;s time to get back to work! Thank you all for reading. Thank you for constant support and your kind words. I read all of your comments on Youtube, on social networks, and the messages you send me via email. It&amp;rsquo;s really heartwarming to see some of you following everything that&amp;rsquo;s happening on a weekly basis. Big thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May update: Krita brushes and ConciseCSS</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/news/2016/new-website-and-krita-brushes-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 13:11:19 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/news/2016/new-website-and-krita-brushes-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;May has been a busy month. I did my best to keep up with everyone on social networks, to give a hand to the Krita developers, with their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AjIiI8uiVNM&#34;&gt;Kickstarter campaign&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip; But I didn&amp;rsquo;t take the time to write longer news posts like this one. Time to share the news for this month! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, I&amp;rsquo;m still catching up with work, since I got that shoulder injury. Thankfully, I got faster in some areas, especially answering people online, thus I&amp;rsquo;m making good progress. On to the news!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div grid&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;card-box&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;card-image&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2016/05/krita-logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Featured picture&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;h3 class=&#34;card-title&#34;&gt;Krita 3 launch Youtube livestream&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;card-content&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Krita 3 is out tomorrow! I will be live on YouTube to answer all of your questions about the program, GDquest, and game art in general. I will also create 2-D game assets to fill in the blanks. To join the event, click on the link below and show up tomorrow, at 6 PM &lt;abbr title=&#34;Central Europe Standard Time (UTC/GMT +2)&#34;&gt;CEST&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

    
    &lt;div class=&#34;card-footer text--center&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hlcHDRc-gN8&#34;&gt;Youtube Livestream&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;krita-brushes-may-update&#34;&gt;Krita brushes May update&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you know, I&amp;rsquo;ve made a set of &lt;a href=&#34;https://gum.co/krita-brushes-for-game-artists&#34;&gt;Krita brushes for game artists&lt;/a&gt;, available on Gumroad. It was initially meant to just be a simple brush pack, I started adding video tutorials on top of it last week to explain what each preset was designed for. This month&amp;rsquo;s update adds 2 new blending brushes: both a round and a flat one. These work a bit like the regular mixing brushes, but they only blend existing colors on the selected layer. They are way softer than existing presets to help you shade extremely smooth surfaces like silk, skin, clouds, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2016/05/krita-brushes-update-may-2016.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Picture: The brushes on the pop-up palette&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will now find 2 tutorials along with the brushes. The first one is dedicated to the mix brushes, and it will show you how to play with the opacity setting to get the most out of them. The 2nd one explains how to use the smear brushes in practice. They may seem strange at first, but trust me, they are actually quite useful! On top of that, I updated the existing brushes to make them less resource intensive. The Paint_Painterly preset comes with a new custom brush tip, and it should be at least 3 or 4 times faster now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gdquest-s-upgrade&#34;&gt;Gdquest&amp;rsquo;s upgrade&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new version of the website is available! I ported it to a new SASS framework, &lt;a href=&#34;http://concisecss.com/&#34;&gt;ConciseCSS&lt;/a&gt;. Some things have changed visually, hopefully for the better. But more importantly, under the hood, everything is different. With the same functionality, the website&amp;rsquo;s Go templates are about 20% shorter. The CSS is smaller, and now I have full control over everything. Not only was the port fast to do, but now I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to improve GDquest faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before that, I was using &lt;a href=&#34;http://getbootstrap.com/&#34;&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;, one of the most popular frameworks out there, made by Twitter. It is very good, but it&amp;rsquo;s also huge. It has everything you&amp;rsquo;d ever need, as well as everything you would never need. Because of that, customizing the style of your website can take a lot of time. That&amp;rsquo;s why I switched to Concise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting with the next version, I will also release the website&amp;rsquo;s code open source. That way, those of you who want a powerful system to create a tutorial/blog oriented website will have an option based on Hugo, a blazing fast, open source static website engine. Right now, the website handles posts, course pages, course summaries, and has some simple modules if you&amp;rsquo;d like to create a blog page for instance. The next version will add templates to render a to do list, to render FAQs, to create a landing page, but also to create a tutorial/articles library!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;next-up&#34;&gt;Next up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;June is going to be a busy month! From June 13 to 19, I&amp;rsquo;ll be at the Randa meetings in Switzerland to work on Krita education, and to meet dozens of passionate KDE developers. The Randa meetings are a yearly open source development sprint. Developers gather from all around the world and share experience with one another to push their respective projects forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that Krita 3 is coming out, I&amp;rsquo;m focusing on video tutorials dedicated to the new version. I plan to create about a dozen. Then, I&amp;rsquo;ll move on to chapter 3 of the Krita tutorial for game artists, which will run you through the game assets creation workflow. This chapter is going to be an entire little training in itself, and a great occasion to put everything you&amp;rsquo;ve learned so far in the training in practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wraps up this month&amp;rsquo;s update. Thank you kindly for your time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;See you soon,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nathan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PS: Don&amp;rsquo;t forget the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/krita/krita-2016-lets-make-text-and-vector-art-awesome&#34;&gt;Krita 2016 Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;. It ends in 8 days.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorials</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 20:29:44 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/tutorial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- TODO: Sub page like &#34;Krita tutorial series&#34; for SEO --&gt;

&lt;!-- TODO: Page per type of tutorial/category --&gt;

&lt;!-- Hey there, it&#39;s the tutorial page! --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you found this page, well, it&amp;rsquo;s in construction! Please come back later :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in Krita 3.0? Krita Review</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/new-features-in-krita-3</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 17:49:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/new-features-in-krita-3</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;text-muted&#34;&gt;Never heard of Krita? It is a free, open source digital painting program that used to be Linux-only. Since 2 years though, there&amp;rsquo;s a Windows version, and the program is now being ported to Mac.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krita 3 is a major update to an already powerful application. It brings it to a whole new level. It ships with a new rendering engine, a traditional animation toolset, an overhauled layers docker, rulers, grid, guides, snapping support, and a brand-new tablet code, which supports more Wacom alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/k51OK2PlTz4&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not all. There&amp;rsquo;s a long list of smaller, yet welcome changes. The pop-up palette looks better and the icons now scale to accommodate for more than 10 brushes. The layer picking and move tools are more flexible. There is a new gradient mapping filter for color grading, as well as an original blending mode for smooth painting with transparent pixel brushes. The keyboard shortcut editor has been redesigned and moved to Krita&amp;rsquo;s preference window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list could go on, and on. You get it: there is a lot to talk about. That&amp;rsquo;s why I wrote this overview of Krita 3. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll introduce you to the most important new features one at a time. At the end of the post, I&amp;rsquo;ll give you my thoughts on the program and the updates for 2-D game artists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you want to learn all of the new features? I&amp;rsquo;m working on a free &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/volume-1/krita-tutorial-for-game-artists&#34;&gt;Krita tutorial series&lt;/a&gt; that will help you to become a faster artist with Krita 3.0.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/volume-1/course/bandcamp-banner.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Krita tutorial series: Become a better Game Artist with Krita&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;!-- Part 1 --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;major-new-features&#34;&gt;Krita 3&amp;rsquo;s New Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krita 3.0 was initially funded by a thousand of backers on Kickstarter in 2015. The campaign had 2 goals: to fund a new, faster rendering engine for digital painting and a traditional animation toolset. This major update brings those additions to the world, and more! Intriguing, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s explore all of Krita 3&amp;rsquo;s new features in details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;instant-preview-the-new-rendering-engine&#34;&gt;Instant Preview: the new rendering engine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krita&amp;rsquo;s performances used to be a major issue for professional work. Painting on large documents would be slow and painful. It&amp;rsquo;s now a matter of the past, at least for the most part: thanks to the Instant Preview, the program is way more responsive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is both simple and powerful: Krita gives you an instant preview of your drawing operations and, at the same time, it takes care of the big calculations in the background. What you get, as the artist, is better feedback on your work. You no longer have to wait for endless seconds between large brushstrokes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The developers completely changed how Krita handles rendering operations under the hood. Thus, the instant preview not only affects brushstrokes, like it was initially meant to. It also works with filters, with the move tool, and with animation playback right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c9yiBRFQnbo&#34;&gt;Overview of the Instant Preview beta in Krita 2.9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/krita/new-in-krita-3/krita-instant-preview-2.9.png&#34; alt=&#34;Instant preview in Krita 2.9 anim edition&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;krita-s-animation-tools&#34;&gt;Krita&amp;rsquo;s animation tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, you read well. You can now animate in Krita! Version 3 comes with a solid toolset that traditional animators will love. And the development team has plans to make it even better in the future. There are 3 new dockers: animation, timeline and onion skin. They respectively allow you to change your animation&amp;rsquo;s length, to manage your frames and your animation layers, and to control your onion skin, a popular effect to preview multiple frames on the canvas at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help you get started animating, there is a new default animation workspace. When you load it, it will display the 3 dockers I just mentioned at the bottom of your interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/krita/new-in-krita-3/krita-3-animation-workspace.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Krita&amp;#39;s animation workspace&#34; /&gt;
    
    

    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;text--muted&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Krita&amp;#39;s animation workspace
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;For more information on this feature, check out my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9uvju6sUNJA&#34;&gt;Krita animation tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.krita.org/Animation&#34;&gt;official Krita docs&lt;/a&gt; will provide offer you with more information if you want to learn every function the toolset provides&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-new-layers-docker-small-my-favorite-feature-small&#34;&gt;The new layers docker &lt;small&gt;My favorite feature&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the change I love the most: layer management is now both much faster and way more flexible. The team redesigned the layers docker from the ground up. It ships with a more compact look, a ton of new functions, keyboard shortcuts&amp;hellip; Almost everything a game artist needs to do his job in the best of conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me outline some of the changes for you. You can now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tag layers and filter them by color.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Manipulate layers and navigate the layer stack with the keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Group, ungroup layers, and add clipping groups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit properties on multiple layers at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last, but not least: the former 3 display modes have been merged into a single one that gives you all of the options you need at a glance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/krita/new-in-krita-3/krita-3-new-layers-docker.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Krita 3&amp;#39;s new layers docker, with layer colors&#34; /&gt;
    
    

    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;text--muted&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Krita 3&amp;#39;s new layers docker, with layer colors
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;rulers-grid-guides-and-snapping&#34;&gt;Rulers, grid, guides and snapping&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are 3 different features that work together. The grid and rulers are both managed in the same docker, called &amp;laquo;grid and guides&amp;raquo;. The grid tab replaces the toolbox&amp;rsquo;s grid tool. Is it a more flexible version of it. The guides, however, are brand new. They are horizontal or vertical lines that you can place wherever you want on the canvas. You can then use them as a reference to lay your layers out accurately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guides are not too interesting in themselves. That&amp;rsquo;s why snapping was also implemented. If you press shift S on your document, a drop-down menu will pop up. It lists a handful of snapping options for you to toggle on or off. Snapping works with grid and guides, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t end there. It also works with vector shapes, with the geometric tools, with the free transform tool, and more. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t work in every situation just yet, but this opens up a whole new range of possibilities within Krita.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-port-to-qt-5-and-kde-frameworks-5&#34;&gt;The port to Qt 5 and KDE frameworks 5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the hood, Krita&amp;rsquo;s code went through major changes. The developers ported the program to Qt 5 and the KDE frameworks 5. These popular code libraries power Krita&amp;rsquo;s interface. They are part of the application&amp;rsquo;s foundations. The port was a massive task, but it will give the team a stable ground for future updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this was made possible thanks to the community and the Kickstarter backers in particular. Speaking of which&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/krita/krita-2016-lets-make-text-and-vector-art-awesome&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/krita/new-in-krita-3/support-krita-2016-kickstarter.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Support Krita&amp;#39;s Kickstarter campaign: Let&amp;#39;s Make Text and Vector Art Awesome!&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The 2016 Kickstarter campaign is live right now, and the developers need your support. Check it out now and help Krita to become even more awesome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;span class=&#34;lead&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/krita/krita-2016-lets-make-text-and-vector-art-awesome
&#34;&gt;Krita 2016: Let&#39;s Make Text and Vector Art Awesome!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;smaller-features&#34;&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re not done yet! &lt;small&gt;11 smaller new features&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for the big additions to Krita 3. But we are not done yet. There is a lot more we need to cover. A lot of small, welcome new features that add up to turn Krita into a better application all-round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-tablet-support-code&#34;&gt;New tablet support code&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I told you in the introduction, the tablet code has been rewritten from scratch. Krita 2.9 would just not recognize a variety of tablets. Version 3, on the other hand, already supports more devices. Especially Wacom alternatives! In case you couldn’t use your tablet in the previous version, you should definitely give it a try again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;improved-layer-picking-and-move-tools&#34;&gt;Improved layer picking and move tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now pick multiple layers at the same time with the R key. Just keep the Shift key down and click on the canvas to add layers to your selection. You can also drag your cursor across the document with both the R and the Shift keys down, and Krita will pick all of the layers under your cursor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move tool got some love as well. You can now nudge your selection around with the arrow keys. If you keep the Shift key down and press an arrow, your layer will move by 10 pixels in the direction of your choice. Without Shift, it will move in one pixel increments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-ui-for-the-assistants&#34;&gt;New UI for the assistants&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The assistants now have a little widget attached to them to control each and every instance separately. The little UI elements move along with the origin of the assistants to help you keep track of them more easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/krita/new-in-krita-3/krita-3-improved-assistant-widget.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The improved assistant widget&#34; /&gt;
    
    

    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;text--muted&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        The improved assistant widget
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;improved-keyboard-shortcuts-editor&#34;&gt;Improved keyboard shortcuts editor&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The keyboard shortcut editor has moved to Krita&amp;rsquo;s preferences. It sits next to the &amp;laquo;Canvas Input Settings&amp;raquo;, where you can edit all canvas related shortcuts. It feels more natural to edit all of the program&amp;rsquo;s options in that unique pop up window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The keyboard shortcuts are now arranged in categories. Unlike before, you can create shortcut schemes to share online. Krita ships with 3 default schemes: the default one, &amp;laquo;Photoshop compatible&amp;raquo; and &amp;laquo;Paint Tool SAI compatible&amp;raquo;. The canvas input settings also come with the same 3 shortcut schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/krita/new-in-krita-3/krita-3-the-shortcut-editor.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Krita 3 editing shortcuts&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;gradient-mapping&#34;&gt;Gradient mapping&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now do quick split toning with the gradient map filter! It was not planned for this release, and it is still a work in progress. The filter doesn&amp;rsquo;t take advantage of the instant preview yet. It is not available as a filter layer, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t preserve your layer&amp;rsquo;s alpha channel. But I&amp;rsquo;m sure game artists will love the addition regardless!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;greater-blending-mode&#34;&gt;Greater blending mode&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a new blending mode in the &amp;laquo;mix&amp;raquo; category, humbly named Greater. I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen something like that in another painting program, but you know what? It&amp;rsquo;s great! With the pixel brush engine, overlapping transparent strokes look ugly in normal mode. They don&amp;rsquo;t blend smoothly, but that&amp;rsquo;s how normal blending works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The greater blending mode solve this issue. It prevents new strokes from increasing the opacity of existing pixels on the canvas beyond your current maximum opacity setting. It may not sound intuitive, but it does feel very natural when you use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/krita/new-in-krita-3/krita-3-greater-blending-mode.png&#34; alt=&#34;Normal (left) vs greater blending mode (right)&#34; /&gt;
    
    

    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;text--muted&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Normal (left) vs greater blending mode (right)
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;gimp-brushes-support-loading-and-saving&#34;&gt;Gimp brushes support (loading and saving)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now both load and save animated brush tips using Gimp&amp;rsquo;s GIH format. This works a bit like importing Photoshop&amp;rsquo;s ABR files: Krita will load the brush tip and add it to your library. For this to work, you have to use the &amp;laquo;Import Resources&amp;raquo; button in the brush preset editor. If your Gimp file contains multiple layers, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to import them as an animated brush tip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/krita/new-in-krita-3/krita-3-loading-and-saving-gimp-brushes.png&#34; alt=&#34;Krita now loads and saves brush tips in Gimp’s format&#34; /&gt;
    
    

    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;text--muted&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Krita now loads and saves brush tips in Gimp’s format
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;improved-pop-up-palette&#34;&gt;Improved pop-up palette&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pop-up palette got a little polish in this version. The brush icons are now displayed as circles, so they&amp;rsquo;ll always show most of the preset&amp;rsquo;s thumbnail. They also automatically resize based on the amount of brushes you want to display. It is easier to pick the right brush among a dozen or more now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/krita/new-in-krita-3/krita-3-color-palette-new-look.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Krita&amp;#39;s new pop-up palette has round icons&#34; /&gt;
    
    

    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;text--muted&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Krita&amp;#39;s new pop-up palette has round icons
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;stable-and-faster-gmic-on-windows&#34;&gt;Stable and faster GMIC on windows&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GMIC, the open source image processor, is now stable on Windows. No more violent crashes! Not only that, it now uses all of your CPU threads for rendering, thus it is much faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find it at the bottom of the filter menu. This tool is a library of more than 400 image effects. They range from simple artistic filters, blurs and sharpen masks to powerful layer splitting tools, as shown in this comic book coloring tutorial by David Revoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YigbVY9s6gU&#34;&gt;Krita 2.9 tutorial - Gmic colorize by David Revoy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;import-and-export-pdf-windows&#34;&gt;Import and export PDF (Windows)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was already possible on Linux, but not on Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s operating system. In Krita 3, you can both load and export PDF files on Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;windows-shell-extension&#34;&gt;Windows shell extension&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great addition for Windows users is the new shell extension. This tiny program gives Windows Explorer the ability to display thumbnails and metadata for your Krita files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/krita/new-in-krita-3/krita-3-windows-shell-extension.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Preview your Krita files from the Explorer with the shell extension&#34; /&gt;
    
    

    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;text--muted&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Preview your Krita files from the Explorer with the shell extension
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;and-more&#34;&gt;And more!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since May 2015, the development team released 11 updates for Krita 2.9. These brought a wide range of improvements to the program. As you can guess, a lot has changed since last year, to the point where there is just too much to talk about! I made a video a few months ago to highlight some of those changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PIKfrqk09Hk&#34;&gt;Krita&amp;rsquo;s New Features since v2.9.5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;krita-review&#34;&gt;Krita Review: My Verdict after 9 Months&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you know what Krita 3 has in store for you. But if you have never heard of Krita, or if you barely used it, you might wonder: is it good? Should I give it a try?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been following Krita&amp;rsquo;s progress since the first Windows release, version 2.8. At first, I found it quite impressive &lt;em&gt;for an open source project&lt;/em&gt;, but it was way behind mainstream programs for game artists. It was unstable, slow, and it lacked too many features for me to do my job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m really picky with the programs I choose. I only work with tools that are flexible and that feel well-designed. Although I&amp;rsquo;m deeply interested in open source, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t shoot myself in the foot just for the sake of using open source tools. I still use Microsoft office and FL studio in my work for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with both Krita and Photoshop side-by-side for the past 9 months. If I have done so, it is only because the experience was satisfying. Krita has some unique tools to its name. You can draw in horizontal, vertical and radial symmetry. There is a built-in brush stabilizer. Perspective guides. It is not perfect. Performances have been a major drawback. You have to work on big documents as a 2-D game artist, and Krita 2.9 didn&amp;rsquo;t like that. But again, this is mostly fixed in Krita 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krita is great when it comes to painting. As far as games are concerned, it is a great tool for character design, environment design and hand-painted textures. Heck, even for animation! If you specialize in one of those fields, I bet you’ll like it! However, right now, it is not the best tool for everything. It is far from ideal when it comes to creating user interface. And you cannot batch export your sprites directly from the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34;&gt;Final thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest: Krita still isn&amp;rsquo;t the ultimate solution for game artists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, it is a great application. And a healthy open-source project. The developers release updates almost monthly. They listen to the community, which is invaluable in my opinion. They take anyone&amp;rsquo;s feedback in account as long as it&amp;rsquo;s constructive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as I&amp;rsquo;m concerned, the program is mature for professional use. It&amp;rsquo;s not perfect, but it&amp;rsquo;s powerful. It easily competes with many paid alternatives I&amp;rsquo;ve tried in the past. Give Krita 3 a try. See what it has in store for you. You won&amp;rsquo;t regret it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;span class=&#34;text--muted&#34;&gt;
Krita 3 is coming out at the end of the month. However, it is already out in Beta, and all of the features listed above are in.
&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://krita.org/item/new-development-builds-ready/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;my-fa fa-link
 text--inherit&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 Krita 3.0 Beta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://krita.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;my-fa fa-link
 text--inherit&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 Krita&amp;rsquo;s official website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/krita/krita-2016-lets-make-text-and-vector-art-awesome&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;my-fa fa-link
 text--inherit&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 The 2016 Krita Kickstarter campaign&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Tips: Concatenate paths with variables</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/programming/hugo-tips-concat-node-paths-variable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 09:34:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/programming/hugo-tips-concat-node-paths-variable/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;text-muted&#34;&gt; This tutorial is a post I initially wrote on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; forums. Hugo is the static website generator that powers GDquest.
It is a really flexible and elegant system, based on Google&amp;rsquo;s Go programming language. Sometimes, it is a bit hard to use for a non-tech-savvy user. So I decided to share some tips on things that got me stuck at some point. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a template, you sometimes need to load data from a path based on a parameter in your content file’s front matter. For example, you may want to add an author to every post that tells the visitor a bit more about the writer. You want to tell Hugo who the author is, and let the template load all of that person’s info from the data folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step is simple. We just have to properly set the author variable in the post’s front matter. We will use it to access the right file in our database:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;+++
author = &amp;quot;nathan&amp;quot;
+++
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on this variable, in your template/partial, you want to access a specific data file stored in the &lt;strong&gt;data/authors/&lt;/strong&gt; folder of your website, named exactly the same as your author variable in your content piece. In my case, this file is &lt;strong&gt;data/authors/admin.toml&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The content of this file can be accessed from your template using the following node path: &lt;strong&gt;.Site.Data.authors.admin&lt;/strong&gt;
The problem is, we don’t always want to have the page’s author set to Admin. If a guest writes a post for my website, I want to use his name instead. For every content piece, the author’s name is available at &lt;strong&gt;.Params.author&lt;/strong&gt; in your template, as we added this variable to our content&amp;rsquo;s front matter. So you want to load the data from the file at &lt;strong&gt;.Site.Data.authors&lt;/strong&gt; called the same as the variable &lt;strong&gt;.Params.author&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do that, in go template, we have to use the index function. Index takes 2 parameters: the first one is a node path, and the 2nd one is a string corresponding to the data we want to access. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{ index .Site.Data.authors “admin” }}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will return the content of .Site.Data.authors.admin. Now, as the variable .Params.author is a string, we can use it with the index function. So this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{ index .Site.Data.authors .Params.author }}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will return the content of the data file at data/authors/our_post_author.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can put your index operation in parentheses and keep going down the node tree by adding a “.” right after it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{ (index .Site.Data “authors”).admin}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, by nesting parentheses, you can compound multiple index operations together and access more complex paths that way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{ index (index .Site.Data &amp;quot;authors&amp;quot;) &amp;quot;admin&amp;quot; }}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see the resulting author banner at the bottom of this post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this helps! As a non-web developer, I find it hard sometimes to wrap my head around the way go template work. It&amp;rsquo;s really simple once you know how to do it, but it can take a while before you find how to use a function the right way, even with the help of the documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Happy Hugo coding!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to monster design for 2-D games</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/tutorial/monster_design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 15:25:47 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/tutorial/monster_design/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;!-- CURRENTLY SET TO EMPTY LAYOUT! --&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;intro-to-monster-design-for-2-d-games&#34;&gt;Intro to monster design for 2-D games&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The intro to monster design is the first free training released on GDquest. In about 40 minutes, it will &lt;strong&gt;run you through the thought process a game artist might follow to design monsters&lt;/strong&gt;. It both covers the thought process behind the design of a monster and an example of monster drawing with pen, paper and Krita.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hahahugoshortcode-1hbhb-useful-links&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;my-fa fa-link
text--default
 text--inherit&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 Useful links&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;my-fa fa-facebook
text--info
 text--inherit&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/GameArtQuest/&#34;&gt;Facebook Game Art study group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;my-fa fa-paint-brush
text--info
 text--inherit&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/krita-brushes-for-game-artists&#34;&gt;GAQ Krita brush pack&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i class=&#34;my-fa fa-shopping-cart
text--success
 text--inherit&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommended graphic tablets</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/recommended-graphic-tablets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 10:08:53 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/recommended-graphic-tablets/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/hardware/huion-vs-wacom.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Huion vs Wacom graphic tablet banner&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;recommended-graphic-tablets&#34;&gt;Recommended graphic tablets&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this page, you can find a list of the graphic tablets I recommend for &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest&#34;&gt;Game Art Quest&lt;/a&gt;. I used &lt;a href=&#34;http://frenden.com/tagged/review&#34;&gt;Frenden&amp;rsquo;s reviews&lt;/a&gt; as a reference to pick affordable tablets you can try out. I also asked feedback to fellow professionals who use Huion devices, as I only have Wacom tablets here. When you buy a graphic tablet, be sure to test your device and to use your right of withdrawal in case you don&amp;rsquo;t like it. And read reviews on Amazon or on the website you&amp;rsquo;re buying them on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;flat-tablets&#34;&gt;Flat tablets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flat tablets are perfect for everyone to start with at a low price. Especially students and hobbyists.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huion H610 pro (80$) - &lt;a href=&#34;http://frenden.com/post/87110791272/huion-h610-pro-h610-k58-graphics-tablet-review&#34;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wacom Intuos Pro Medium or Large (300-500$)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;screen-tablets&#34;&gt;Screen tablets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Screen tablets are worth a try if you&amp;rsquo;re an experienced artist already, and you do a lot of line work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huion GT-220 (21.5&amp;raquo; HD screen, 800$) - &lt;a href=&#34;http://frenden.com/image/118056589592&#34;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monoprice 19&amp;raquo; (1440*900 resolution, 400$) - &lt;a href=&#34;http://frenden.com/post/69444810884/review-monoprice-19-tablet-monitor-wacom-take&#34;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wacom Cintiq 13HD (13&amp;raquo; HD screen, 800$)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tips&#34;&gt;Tips&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always&lt;/strong&gt; download and install the driver from the manufacturer&amp;rsquo;s official website &lt;strong&gt;before&lt;/strong&gt; you plug your device in! This will save you some trouble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As far as Wacom tablets are concerned, you can pretty safely buy second hand devices! That&amp;rsquo;s how I got mine, and after years of frequent use, they still work perfectly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the time I&amp;rsquo;m writing this, Krita doesn&amp;rsquo;t support every single tablet on the market. The developers are in the process of re-writing their tablet code. Wacom tablets work OK, but some other brands might not until Krita 3.0&amp;rsquo;s release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to use 2 tablets at the same time like I&amp;rsquo;m doing, they have to share the same brand. In other words, you can&amp;rsquo;t use a flat Wacom tablet and a Wacom cintiq at the same time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDquest news and Krita 3.0 pre-alpha 3</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/community/GDquest-news-and-Krita-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 08:25:29 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/community/GDquest-news-and-Krita-3/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/JWwpm4hs0l0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Hi there! I wanted to keep you posted on what is going on right now with GDquest. The video says it all, but I’m going to sum up the news below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With one last contract finished last week, and the series on monster design done, I am now working full-time on Game Art Quest. My top priority is to release the first version of the GAQ Krita brush back and to finish chapter 0 in the training. Once this is done, I will start releasing videos from the training publicly, at the rate of 1 to 2 per week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I released the first 5 soundtracks from the project in an album called &lt;a href=&#34;https://gdquest.bandcamp.com/album/space-adventures&#34;&gt;Space Adventures&lt;/a&gt;. They are available under the &lt;strong&gt;Creative Commons 4.0 license&lt;/strong&gt;, so you can use them in &lt;strong&gt;both personal and commercial projects&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&#34;border: 0; width: 700px; height: 307px;&#34; src=&#34;https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1579881958/size=large/bgcol=333333/linkcol=e99708/artwork=small/transparent=true/&#34; seamless&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.bandcamp.com/album/space-adventures&#34;&gt;Space adventures by Nathan Lovato&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-votes-for-future-tutorials&#34;&gt;Your votes for future tutorials&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since January, I have been &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/post/community/vote-for-upcoming-tutorials-january-2016/&#34;&gt;running a vote&lt;/a&gt; to ask you which tutorial series you wanted me to do this year aside from Krita. More than 400 people voted, and here are the themes you picked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview of Godot 2.0, the open source game engine, for 2d games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Painting rock and grass tiles for 2d games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Human proportions, from reality to games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is great, as they will reinforce &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest&#34;&gt;Game Art Quest&lt;/a&gt;. I might also do the 4th one, the Overview of &lt;a href=&#34;http://superpowers-html5.com/&#34;&gt;Superpowers, the collaborative HTML5 game engine&lt;/a&gt;, as time permits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;krita-3-0-pre-alpha-3&#34;&gt;Krita 3.0, pre-alpha 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;\img\post\community\krita-gradient-map.png&#34; alt=&#34;Krita gradient map filter&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 3rd pre-alpha of Krita 3.0 was released! The development entered a feature-frozen state, and the full release of Krita 3.0 is planned for April 27. The features that didn’t make it in this version will be available in Krita 3.1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick list of what is new in this pre-alpha:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The improvements to the layer docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new grid and guides system, along with snapping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A gradient map filter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A greater alpha blending mode, useful for painting with the pixel brush engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The foundations for 2 exporters. One is for spriter, the animation application for 2d games, and the other one is a csv-based format to exports animated sequences from krita.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A variety of improvements to the move tool, the crop tool, the assistants…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Head on to the dedicated article on the official website to find the builds along with download instructions. It also features an exhaustive list of changes in this version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That’s it for this update. See you soon, in the next one!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krita tutorial for Game Artists</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/volume-1/krita-tutorial-for-game-artists</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 17:55:44 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/volume-1/krita-tutorial-for-game-artists</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you want to become a better 2-D game artist, this training is for you&lt;/strong&gt;. It will teach you how to work with Krita, a mature open source digital painting program. In 6 chapters, we will explore the most important features krita has to offer to game artists. Cherry on the cake: the tutorials are completely free! And if you have some experience already and want to go further, I&amp;rsquo;m working on a new &lt;a href=&#34;https://gumroad.com/l/krita-game-art-tutorial-1&#34;&gt;Krita game art workshop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The training has moved!</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/volume-1/course</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 17:55:44 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/volume-1/course</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Hi! If you&amp;rsquo;re here, you&amp;rsquo;re certainly a backer of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/gdquest/game-art-quest-make-professional-2d-art-with-krita&#34;&gt;Game Art Quest&lt;/a&gt; Kickstarter campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved the course to &lt;a href=&#34;https://gumroad.com/l/krita-tutorial-for-game-artists&#34;&gt;Gumroad&lt;/a&gt;, the same place where you got your premium brushes. Thanks to that change, you can now download the tutorials to watch offline! I sent &lt;strong&gt;your personal coupon code via email&lt;/strong&gt; so you can get an instant free access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-redeem-your-coupon&#34;&gt;How to redeem your coupon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the email, you will find a link that will automatically apply your coupon for you. The price of the product should be crossed and replaced with &amp;laquo;€0&amp;raquo;. Click the &amp;laquo;I want this!&amp;raquo; button and enter your email address to add the course to your Gumroad library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/page/game-art-quest/krita-tutorial-coupon-redeem.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Coupon code redeem example&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you go, you can now stream the videos directly on Gumroad or download them all to watch later!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>