<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on GDquest</title>
    <link>http://gdquest.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on GDquest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 11:17:06 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://gdquest.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>June update: the Randa meetings</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/06/kickstarter-news-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 11:17:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/06/kickstarter-news-june/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re getting to the end of June. It&amp;rsquo;s time to sum up all that&amp;rsquo;s been happening this month. The short version: I kept improving the website, went to the biggest yearly KDE development sprint in Randa, Switzerland, and added about 1h of tutorials dedicated to Krita 3&amp;rsquo;s new features in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/volume-1/krita-tutorial-for-game-artists/&#34;&gt;Krita training&lt;/a&gt;. You can find more details about what happened in Randa, and what the plans are for July, below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;randa&#34;&gt;Randa&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From June 13 to 19, I was in Randa, KDE&amp;rsquo;s biggest yearly sprint. KDE is a large community of free software developers and users. Krita is part of it, and it&amp;rsquo;s certainly the most popular multiplatform KDE program today. Sadly, no one else from the team could make it to the sprint this year. They ran a hectic Kickstarter in May, and boud, Krita&amp;rsquo;s maintainer, had too much work to do the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Randa was an amazing experience for me. There, I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to produce Krita tutorials. I mostly jumped around projects, learned about the whole KDE ecosystem, and helped with communication and UX design. It&amp;rsquo;s incredible to get in touch with so many cultures at once. People came from all around the world. There was Joseph, from Kenya, who came to port KDEnlive on Windows. Lays and Ayrton, from Brazil, working on an open 3d printing program. Developers from India, Germany, Denmark&amp;hellip; you name it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2016/06/Randa-meetings-work-discussions.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;KDE Randa meetings: developers discussions&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All those people are so different&amp;hellip; and yet they all work together to hopefully make the computer world a slightly better place. There was such a strong ambience there that we all worked very hard. I was up around 7:00 every morning, and went off to bed at 23:00. I spent the vast majority of the day working. And it was pretty much the same for everybody else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The village we stayed at itself was peaceful and lovely. A perfect, undistracted place to both focus and relax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2016/06/Randa-view-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Randa view of the mountains&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The view was gorgeous from my office&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;time-to-make-some-money-again&#34;&gt;Time to make some money again&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I told you in a previous update, Game Art Quest became bigger than what it was supposed to be. With the Kickstarter, we raised enough money for six months of full-time work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These six months are getting to an end, so I have to make a bit of money again. I&amp;rsquo;m getting new offers on a weekly basis, but until now, I almost declined them all. However, I accepted one job writing Krita tutorials for a magazine this month. It is a great opportunity as they asked me to work on animation, which I haven&amp;rsquo;t covered yet in the training, thus it&amp;rsquo;s not distracting me from daily work too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking to start working on and selling the next 2 volumes of the training in early access at the end of July. If I sell enough, I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to keep working full-time on it. Otherwise, I&amp;rsquo;ll dedicate one day per week to client work, which shouldn&amp;rsquo;t slow down the production of the training noticeably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;this-week&#34;&gt;This week&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To wrap up June, I have to release a brush pack update. This new version will contain 4 new brushes, and I painted a new thumbnail for the blender brush, as the current one looks horrible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2016/06/Flat-blender-brush.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;New flat blender brush icon&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I&amp;rsquo;m working on the fourth chapter in the Krita training, to release it as soon as possible. It will introduce you to the game assets creation workflow. As soon as it is out, I will move on to the second volume of the training, which you will be able to access on Gumroad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving into July, I have to get working again on the blender of VSE add-on. It is one of the main ways I can improve my productivity creating the video tutorials now. My goal is to add one new feature every single week, even if it&amp;rsquo;s small. This week for instance, I&amp;rsquo;m working on an import feature that loads all of the project&amp;rsquo;s video and audio files to the VSE in one click. As I get to create up to six videos in a single week, this feature will be a real time saver. And with that, I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to release the first public version of the add-on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2016/06/blender-vse-add-on-code.png&#34; alt=&#34;Blender GDquest VSE add-on import code&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The import code is already there - it just needs to be refined&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, it&amp;rsquo;s time to get back to work! Thank you all for reading. Thank you for constant support and your kind words. I read all of your comments on Youtube, on social networks, and the messages you send me via email. It&amp;rsquo;s really heartwarming to see some of you following everything that&amp;rsquo;s happening on a weekly basis. Big thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May update: Krita brushes and ConciseCSS</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/05/new-website-and-krita-brushes-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 13:11:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/05/new-website-and-krita-brushes-update/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;May has been a busy month. I did my best to keep up with everyone on social networks, to give a hand to the Krita developers, with their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AjIiI8uiVNM&#34;&gt;Kickstarter campaign&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip; But I didn&amp;rsquo;t take the time to write longer news posts like this one. Time to share the news for this month!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, I&amp;rsquo;m still catching up with work, since I got that shoulder injury. Thankfully, I got faster in some areas, especially answering people online, thus I&amp;rsquo;m making good progress. On to the news!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div row column=12&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;card&#34;&gt;
    
    &lt;div class=&#34;card-image&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2016/05/krita-logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Featured picture&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    

    
    &lt;h3 class=&#34;card-title&#34;&gt;
      Krita 3 launch Youtube livestream
    &lt;/h3&gt;
    

    
    &lt;div class=&#34;card-content&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
        Krita 3 is out tomorrow! I will be live on YouTube to answer all of your questions about the program, GDquest, and game art in general. I will also create 2-D game assets to fill in the blanks. To join the event, click on the link below and show up tomorrow, at 6 PM &lt;abbr title=&#34;Central Europe Standard Time (UTC/GMT +2)&#34;&gt;CEST&lt;/abbr&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    

    
    &lt;div class=&#34;card-footer lead&#34; style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hlcHDRc-gN8&#34;&gt;
        Youtube Livestream
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;krita-brushes-may-update&#34;&gt;Krita brushes May update&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you know, I&amp;rsquo;ve made a set of &lt;a href=&#34;https://gum.co/krita-brushes-for-game-artists&#34;&gt;Krita brushes for game artists&lt;/a&gt;, available on Gumroad. It was initially meant to just be a simple brush pack, I started adding video tutorials on top of it last week to explain what each preset was designed for. This month&amp;rsquo;s update adds 2 new blending brushes: both a round and a flat one. These work a bit like the regular mixing brushes, but they only blend existing colors on the selected layer. They are way softer than existing presets to help you shade extremely smooth surfaces like silk, skin, clouds, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2016/05/krita-brushes-update-may-2016.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Picture: The brushes on the pop-up palette&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will now find 2 tutorials along with the brushes. The first one is dedicated to the mix brushes, and it will show you how to play with the opacity setting to get the most out of them. The 2nd one explains how to use the smear brushes in practice. They may seem strange at first, but trust me, they are actually quite useful! On top of that, I updated the existing brushes to make them less resource intensive. The Paint_Painterly preset comes with a new custom brush tip, and it should be at least 3 or 4 times faster now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gdquest-s-upgrade&#34;&gt;Gdquest&amp;rsquo;s upgrade&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new version of the website is available! I ported it to a new SASS framework, &lt;a href=&#34;http://concisecss.com/&#34;&gt;ConciseCSS&lt;/a&gt;. Some things have changed visually, hopefully for the better. But more importantly, under the hood, everything is different. With the same functionality, the website&amp;rsquo;s Go templates are about 20% shorter. The CSS is smaller, and now I have full control over everything. Not only was the port fast to do, but now I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to improve GDquest faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before that, I was using &lt;a href=&#34;http://getbootstrap.com/&#34;&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;, one of the most popular frameworks out there, made by Twitter. It is very good, but it&amp;rsquo;s also huge. It has everything you&amp;rsquo;d ever need, as well as everything you would never need. Because of that, customizing the style of your website can take a lot of time. That&amp;rsquo;s why I switched to Concise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting with the next version, I will also release the website&amp;rsquo;s code open source. That way, those of you who want a powerful system to create a tutorial/blog oriented website will have an option based on Hugo, a blazing fast, open source static website engine. Right now, the website handles posts, course pages, course summaries, and has some simple modules if you&amp;rsquo;d like to create a blog page for instance. The next version will add templates to render a to do list, to render FAQs, to create a landing page, but also to create a tutorial/articles library!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;next-up&#34;&gt;Next up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;June is going to be a busy month! From June 13 to 19, I&amp;rsquo;ll be at the Randa meetings in Switzerland to work on Krita education, and to meet dozens of passionate KDE developers. The Randa meetings are a yearly open source development sprint. Developers gather from all around the world and share experience with one another to push their respective projects forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that Krita 3 is coming out, I&amp;rsquo;m focusing on video tutorials dedicated to the new version. I plan to create about a dozen. Then, I&amp;rsquo;ll move on to chapter 3 of the Krita tutorial for game artists, which will run you through the game assets creation workflow. This chapter is going to be an entire little training in itself, and a great occasion to put everything you&amp;rsquo;ve learned so far in the training in practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wraps up this month&amp;rsquo;s update. Thank you kindly for your time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;See you soon,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nathan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PS: Don&amp;rsquo;t forget the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/krita/krita-2016-lets-make-text-and-vector-art-awesome&#34;&gt;Krita 2016 Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;. It ends in 8 days.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in Krita 3.0? Krita Review</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/new-features-in-krita-3</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 17:49:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/new-features-in-krita-3</guid>
      <description>

&lt;!-- introduction --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;text-muted&#34;&gt;Never heard of Krita? It is a free, open source digital painting program that used to be Linux-only. Since 2 years though, there&amp;rsquo;s a Windows version, and the program is now being ported to Mac.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krita 3 is a major update to an already powerful application. It brings it to a whole new level. It ships with a new rendering engine, a traditional animation toolset, an overhauled layers docker, rulers, grid, guides, snapping support, and a brand-new tablet code, which supports more Wacom alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/k51OK2PlTz4&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not all. There&amp;rsquo;s a long list of smaller, yet welcome changes. The pop-up palette looks better and the icons now scale to accommodate for more than 10 brushes. The layer picking and move tools are more flexible. There is a new gradient mapping filter for color grading, as well as an original blending mode for smooth painting with transparent pixel brushes. The keyboard shortcut editor has been redesigned and moved to Krita&amp;rsquo;s preference window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list could go on, and on. You get it: there is a lot to talk about. That&amp;rsquo;s why I wrote this overview of Krita 3. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll introduce you to the most important new features one at a time. At the end of the post, I&amp;rsquo;ll give you my thoughts on the program and the updates for 2-D game artists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you want to learn all of the new features? I&amp;rsquo;m working on a free &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/volume-1/krita-tutorial-for-game-artists/&#34;&gt;Krita tutorial series&lt;/a&gt; that will help you to become a faster artist with Krita 3.0.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/volume-1/course/bandcamp-banner.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Krita tutorial series: Become a better Game Artist with Krita&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;!-- Part 1 --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;major-new-features&#34;&gt;Krita 3&amp;rsquo;s New Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krita 3.0 was initially funded by a thousand of backers on Kickstarter in 2015. The campaign had 2 goals: to fund a new, faster rendering engine for digital painting and a traditional animation toolset. This major update brings those additions to the world, and more! Intriguing, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s explore all of Krita 3&amp;rsquo;s new features in details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;instant-preview-the-new-rendering-engine&#34;&gt;Instant Preview: the new rendering engine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krita&amp;rsquo;s performances used to be a major issue for professional work. Painting on large documents would be slow and painful. It&amp;rsquo;s now a matter of the past, at least for the most part: thanks to the Instant Preview, the program is way more responsive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is both simple and powerful: Krita gives you an instant preview of your drawing operations and, at the same time, it takes care of the big calculations in the background. What you get, as the artist, is better feedback on your work. You no longer have to wait for endless seconds between large brushstrokes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The developers completely changed how Krita handles rendering operations under the hood. Thus, the instant preview not only affects brushstrokes, like it was initially meant to. It also works with filters, with the move tool, and with animation playback right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c9yiBRFQnbo&#34;&gt;Overview of the Instant Preview beta in Krita 2.9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/krita/new-in-krita-3/krita-instant-preview-2.9.png&#34; alt=&#34;Instant preview in Krita 2.9 anim edition&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;krita-s-animation-tools&#34;&gt;Krita&amp;rsquo;s animation tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, you read well. You can now animate in Krita! Version 3 comes with a solid toolset that traditional animators will love. And the development team has plans to make it even better in the future. There are 3 new dockers: animation, timeline and onion skin. They respectively allow you to change your animation&amp;rsquo;s length, to manage your frames and your animation layers, and to control your onion skin, a popular effect to preview multiple frames on the canvas at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help you get started animating, there is a new default animation workspace. When you load it, it will display the 3 dockers I just mentioned at the bottom of your interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/krita/new-in-krita-3/krita-3-animation-workspace.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Krita&amp;#39;s animation workspace&#34; /&gt;
    
    

    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;text--muted&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Krita&amp;#39;s animation workspace
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;For more information on this feature, check out my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9uvju6sUNJA&#34;&gt;Krita animation tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.krita.org/Animation&#34;&gt;official Krita docs&lt;/a&gt; will provide offer you with more information if you want to learn every function the toolset provides&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-new-layers-docker-small-my-favorite-feature-small&#34;&gt;The new layers docker &lt;small&gt;My favorite feature&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the change I love the most: layer management is now both much faster and way more flexible. The team redesigned the layers docker from the ground up. It ships with a more compact look, a ton of new functions, keyboard shortcuts&amp;hellip; Almost everything a game artist needs to do his job in the best of conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me outline some of the changes for you. You can now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tag layers and filter them by color.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Manipulate layers and navigate the layer stack with the keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Group, ungroup layers, and add clipping groups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit properties on multiple layers at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last, but not least: the former 3 display modes have been merged into a single one that gives you all of the options you need at a glance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/krita/new-in-krita-3/krita-3-new-layers-docker.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Krita 3&amp;#39;s new layers docker, with layer colors&#34; /&gt;
    
    

    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;text--muted&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Krita 3&amp;#39;s new layers docker, with layer colors
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;rulers-grid-guides-and-snapping&#34;&gt;Rulers, grid, guides and snapping&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are 3 different features that work together. The grid and rulers are both managed in the same docker, called &amp;laquo;grid and guides&amp;raquo;. The grid tab replaces the toolbox&amp;rsquo;s grid tool. Is it a more flexible version of it. The guides, however, are brand new. They are horizontal or vertical lines that you can place wherever you want on the canvas. You can then use them as a reference to lay your layers out accurately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guides are not too interesting in themselves. That&amp;rsquo;s why snapping was also implemented. If you press shift S on your document, a drop-down menu will pop up. It lists a handful of snapping options for you to toggle on or off. Snapping works with grid and guides, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t end there. It also works with vector shapes, with the geometric tools, with the free transform tool, and more. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t work in every situation just yet, but this opens up a whole new range of possibilities within Krita.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-port-to-qt-5-and-kde-frameworks-5&#34;&gt;The port to Qt 5 and KDE frameworks 5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the hood, Krita&amp;rsquo;s code went through major changes. The developers ported the program to Qt 5 and the KDE frameworks 5. These popular code libraries power Krita&amp;rsquo;s interface. They are part of the application&amp;rsquo;s foundations. The port was a massive task, but it will give the team a stable ground for future updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this was made possible thanks to the community and the Kickstarter backers in particular. Speaking of which&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/krita/krita-2016-lets-make-text-and-vector-art-awesome&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/krita/new-in-krita-3/support-krita-2016-kickstarter.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Support Krita&amp;#39;s Kickstarter campaign: Let&amp;#39;s Make Text and Vector Art Awesome!&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The 2016 Kickstarter campaign is live right now, and the developers need your support. Check it out now and help Krita to become even more awesome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;span class=&#34;lead&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/krita/krita-2016-lets-make-text-and-vector-art-awesome
&#34;&gt;Krita 2016: Let&#39;s Make Text and Vector Art Awesome!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;smaller-features&#34;&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re not done yet! &lt;small&gt;11 smaller new features&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for the big additions to Krita 3. But we are not done yet. There is a lot more we need to cover. A lot of small, welcome new features that add up to turn Krita into a better application all-round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-tablet-support-code&#34;&gt;New tablet support code&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I told you in the introduction, the tablet code has been rewritten from scratch. Krita 2.9 would just not recognize a variety of tablets. Version 3, on the other hand, already supports more devices. Especially Wacom alternatives! In case you couldn’t use your tablet in the previous version, you should definitely give it a try again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;improved-layer-picking-and-move-tools&#34;&gt;Improved layer picking and move tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now pick multiple layers at the same time with the R key. Just keep the Shift key down and click on the canvas to add layers to your selection. You can also drag your cursor across the document with both the R and the Shift keys down, and Krita will pick all of the layers under your cursor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move tool got some love as well. You can now nudge your selection around with the arrow keys. If you keep the Shift key down and press an arrow, your layer will move by 10 pixels in the direction of your choice. Without Shift, it will move in one pixel increments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-ui-for-the-assistants&#34;&gt;New UI for the assistants&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The assistants now have a little widget attached to them to control each and every instance separately. The little UI elements move along with the origin of the assistants to help you keep track of them more easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/krita/new-in-krita-3/krita-3-improved-assistant-widget.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The improved assistant widget&#34; /&gt;
    
    

    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;text--muted&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        The improved assistant widget
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;improved-keyboard-shortcuts-editor&#34;&gt;Improved keyboard shortcuts editor&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The keyboard shortcut editor has moved to Krita&amp;rsquo;s preferences. It sits next to the &amp;laquo;Canvas Input Settings&amp;raquo;, where you can edit all canvas related shortcuts. It feels more natural to edit all of the program&amp;rsquo;s options in that unique pop up window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The keyboard shortcuts are now arranged in categories. Unlike before, you can create shortcut schemes to share online. Krita ships with 3 default schemes: the default one, &amp;laquo;Photoshop compatible&amp;raquo; and &amp;laquo;Paint Tool SAI compatible&amp;raquo;. The canvas input settings also come with the same 3 shortcut schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/krita/new-in-krita-3/krita-3-the-shortcut-editor.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Krita 3 editing shortcuts&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;gradient-mapping&#34;&gt;Gradient mapping&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now do quick split toning with the gradient map filter! It was not planned for this release, and it is still a work in progress. The filter doesn&amp;rsquo;t take advantage of the instant preview yet. It is not available as a filter layer, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t preserve your layer&amp;rsquo;s alpha channel. But I&amp;rsquo;m sure game artists will love the addition regardless!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;greater-blending-mode&#34;&gt;Greater blending mode&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a new blending mode in the &amp;laquo;mix&amp;raquo; category, humbly named Greater. I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen something like that in another painting program, but you know what? It&amp;rsquo;s great! With the pixel brush engine, overlapping transparent strokes look ugly in normal mode. They don&amp;rsquo;t blend smoothly, but that&amp;rsquo;s how normal blending works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The greater blending mode solve this issue. It prevents new strokes from increasing the opacity of existing pixels on the canvas beyond your current maximum opacity setting. It may not sound intuitive, but it does feel very natural when you use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/krita/new-in-krita-3/krita-3-greater-blending-mode.png&#34; alt=&#34;Normal (left) vs greater blending mode (right)&#34; /&gt;
    
    

    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;text--muted&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Normal (left) vs greater blending mode (right)
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;gimp-brushes-support-loading-and-saving&#34;&gt;Gimp brushes support (loading and saving)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now both load and save animated brush tips using Gimp&amp;rsquo;s GIH format. This works a bit like importing Photoshop&amp;rsquo;s ABR files: Krita will load the brush tip and add it to your library. For this to work, you have to use the &amp;laquo;Import Resources&amp;raquo; button in the brush preset editor. If your Gimp file contains multiple layers, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to import them as an animated brush tip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/krita/new-in-krita-3/krita-3-loading-and-saving-gimp-brushes.png&#34; alt=&#34;Krita now loads and saves brush tips in Gimp’s format&#34; /&gt;
    
    

    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;text--muted&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Krita now loads and saves brush tips in Gimp’s format
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;improved-pop-up-palette&#34;&gt;Improved pop-up palette&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pop-up palette got a little polish in this version. The brush icons are now displayed as circles, so they&amp;rsquo;ll always show most of the preset&amp;rsquo;s thumbnail. They also automatically resize based on the amount of brushes you want to display. It is easier to pick the right brush among a dozen or more now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/krita/new-in-krita-3/krita-3-color-palette-new-look.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Krita&amp;#39;s new pop-up palette has round icons&#34; /&gt;
    
    

    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;text--muted&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Krita&amp;#39;s new pop-up palette has round icons
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;stable-and-faster-gmic-on-windows&#34;&gt;Stable and faster GMIC on windows&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GMIC, the open source image processor, is now stable on Windows. No more violent crashes! Not only that, it now uses all of your CPU threads for rendering, thus it is much faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find it at the bottom of the filter menu. This tool is a library of more than 400 image effects. They range from simple artistic filters, blurs and sharpen masks to powerful layer splitting tools, as shown in this comic book coloring tutorial by David Revoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YigbVY9s6gU&#34;&gt;Krita 2.9 tutorial - Gmic colorize by David Revoy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;import-and-export-pdf-windows&#34;&gt;Import and export PDF (Windows)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was already possible on Linux, but not on Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s operating system. In Krita 3, you can both load and export PDF files on Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;windows-shell-extension&#34;&gt;Windows shell extension&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great addition for Windows users is the new shell extension. This tiny program gives Windows Explorer the ability to display thumbnails and metadata for your Krita files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/krita/new-in-krita-3/krita-3-windows-shell-extension.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Preview your Krita files from the Explorer with the shell extension&#34; /&gt;
    
    

    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;text--muted&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Preview your Krita files from the Explorer with the shell extension
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;and-more&#34;&gt;And more!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since May 2015, the development team released 11 updates for Krita 2.9. These brought a wide range of improvements to the program. As you can guess, a lot has changed since last year, to the point where there is just too much to talk about! I made a video a few months ago to highlight some of those changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PIKfrqk09Hk&#34;&gt;Krita&amp;rsquo;s New Features since v2.9.5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;krita-review&#34;&gt;Krita Review: My Verdict after 9 Months&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you know what Krita 3 has in store for you. But if you have never heard of Krita, or if you barely used it, you might wonder: is it good? Should I give it a try?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been following Krita&amp;rsquo;s progress since the first Windows release, version 2.8. At first, I found it quite impressive &lt;em&gt;for an open source project&lt;/em&gt;, but it was way behind mainstream programs for game artists. It was unstable, slow, and it lacked too many features for me to do my job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m really picky with the programs I choose. I only work with tools that are flexible and that feel well-designed. Although I&amp;rsquo;m deeply interested in open source, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t shoot myself in the foot just for the sake of using open source tools. I still use Microsoft office and FL studio in my work for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with both Krita and Photoshop side-by-side for the past 9 months. If I have done so, it is only because the experience was satisfying. Krita has some unique tools to its name. You can draw in horizontal, vertical and radial symmetry. There is a built-in brush stabilizer. Perspective guides. It is not perfect. Performances have been a major drawback. You have to work on big documents as a 2-D game artist, and Krita 2.9 didn&amp;rsquo;t like that. But again, this is mostly fixed in Krita 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krita is great when it comes to painting. As far as games are concerned, it is a great tool for character design, environment design and hand-painted textures. Heck, even for animation! If you specialize in one of those fields, I bet you’ll like it! However, right now, it is not the best tool for everything. It is far from ideal when it comes to creating user interface. And you cannot batch export your sprites directly from the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34;&gt;Final thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest: Krita still isn&amp;rsquo;t the ultimate solution for game artists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, it is a great application. And a healthy open-source project. The developers release updates almost monthly. They listen to the community, which is invaluable in my opinion. They take anyone&amp;rsquo;s feedback in account as long as it&amp;rsquo;s constructive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as I&amp;rsquo;m concerned, the program is mature for professional use. It&amp;rsquo;s not perfect, but it&amp;rsquo;s powerful. It easily competes with many paid alternatives I&amp;rsquo;ve tried in the past. Give Krita 3 a try. See what it has in store for you. You won&amp;rsquo;t regret it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;span class=&#34;text--muted&#34;&gt;
Krita 3 is coming out at the end of the month. However, it is already out in Beta, and all of the features listed above are in.
&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://krita.org/item/new-development-builds-ready/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;my-fa fa-link
 text--inherit&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 Krita 3.0 Beta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://krita.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;my-fa fa-link
 text--inherit&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 Krita&amp;rsquo;s official website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/krita/krita-2016-lets-make-text-and-vector-art-awesome&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;my-fa fa-link
 text--inherit&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 The 2016 Krita Kickstarter campaign&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Tips: Concatenate paths with variables</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/programming/hugo-tips-concat-node-paths-variable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 09:34:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/programming/hugo-tips-concat-node-paths-variable/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;text-muted&#34;&gt; This tutorial is a post I initially wrote on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; forums. Hugo is the static website generator that powers GDquest.
It is a really flexible and elegant system, based on Google&amp;rsquo;s Go programming language. Sometimes, it is a bit hard to use for a non-tech-savvy user. So I decided to share some tips on things that got me stuck at some point. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a template, you sometimes need to load data from a path based on a parameter in your content file’s front matter. For example, you may want to add an author to every post that tells the visitor a bit more about the writer. You want to tell Hugo who the author is, and let the template load all of that person’s info from the data folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step is simple. We just have to properly set the author variable in the post’s front matter. We will use it to access the right file in our database:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;+++
author = &amp;quot;nathan&amp;quot;
+++
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on this variable, in your template/partial, you want to access a specific data file stored in the &lt;strong&gt;data/authors/&lt;/strong&gt; folder of your website, named exactly the same as your author variable in your content piece. In my case, this file is &lt;strong&gt;data/authors/admin.toml&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The content of this file can be accessed from your template using the following node path: &lt;strong&gt;.Site.Data.authors.admin&lt;/strong&gt;
The problem is, we don’t always want to have the page’s author set to Admin. If a guest writes a post for my website, I want to use his name instead. For every content piece, the author’s name is available at &lt;strong&gt;.Params.author&lt;/strong&gt; in your template, as we added this variable to our content&amp;rsquo;s front matter. So you want to load the data from the file at &lt;strong&gt;.Site.Data.authors&lt;/strong&gt; called the same as the variable &lt;strong&gt;.Params.author&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do that, in go template, we have to use the index function. Index takes 2 parameters: the first one is a node path, and the 2nd one is a string corresponding to the data we want to access. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{ index .Site.Data.authors “admin” }}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will return the content of .Site.Data.authors.admin. Now, as the variable .Params.author is a string, we can use it with the index function. So this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{ index .Site.Data.authors .Params.author }}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will return the content of the data file at data/authors/our_post_author.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can put your index operation in parentheses and keep going down the node tree by adding a “.” right after it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{ (index .Site.Data “authors”).admin}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, by nesting parentheses, you can compound multiple index operations together and access more complex paths that way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{ index (index .Site.Data &amp;quot;authors&amp;quot;) &amp;quot;admin&amp;quot; }}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see the resulting author banner at the bottom of this post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this helps! As a non-web developer, I find it hard sometimes to wrap my head around the way go template work. It&amp;rsquo;s really simple once you know how to do it, but it can take a while before you find how to use a function the right way, even with the help of the documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Happy Hugo coding!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommended graphic tablets</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/recommended-graphic-tablets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 10:08:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/recommended-graphic-tablets/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/hardware/huion-vs-wacom.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Huion vs Wacom graphic tablet banner&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;recommended-graphic-tablets&#34;&gt;Recommended graphic tablets&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this page, you can find a list of the graphic tablets I recommend for &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/&#34;&gt;Game Art Quest&lt;/a&gt;. I used &lt;a href=&#34;http://frenden.com/tagged/review&#34;&gt;Frenden&amp;rsquo;s reviews&lt;/a&gt; as a reference to pick affordable tablets you can try out. I also asked feedback to fellow professionals who use Huion devices, as I only have Wacom tablets here. When you buy a graphic tablet, be sure to test your device and to use your right of withdrawal in case you don&amp;rsquo;t like it. And read reviews on Amazon or on the website you&amp;rsquo;re buying them on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;flat-tablets&#34;&gt;Flat tablets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flat tablets are perfect for everyone to start with at a low price. Especially students and hobbyists.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huion H610 pro (80$) - &lt;a href=&#34;http://frenden.com/post/87110791272/huion-h610-pro-h610-k58-graphics-tablet-review&#34;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wacom Intuos Pro Medium or Large (300-500$)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;screen-tablets&#34;&gt;Screen tablets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Screen tablets are worth a try if you&amp;rsquo;re an experienced artist already, and you do a lot of line work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huion GT-220 (21.5&amp;raquo; HD screen, 800$) - &lt;a href=&#34;http://frenden.com/image/118056589592&#34;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monoprice 19&amp;raquo; (1440*900 resolution, 400$) - &lt;a href=&#34;http://frenden.com/post/69444810884/review-monoprice-19-tablet-monitor-wacom-take&#34;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wacom Cintiq 13HD (13&amp;raquo; HD screen, 800$)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tips&#34;&gt;Tips&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always&lt;/strong&gt; download and install the driver from the manufacturer&amp;rsquo;s official website &lt;strong&gt;before&lt;/strong&gt; you plug your device in! This will save you some trouble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As far as Wacom tablets are concerned, you can pretty safely buy second hand devices! That&amp;rsquo;s how I got mine, and after years of frequent use, they still work perfectly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the time I&amp;rsquo;m writing this, Krita doesn&amp;rsquo;t support every single tablet on the market. The developers are in the process of re-writing their tablet code. Wacom tablets work OK, but some other brands might not until Krita 3.0&amp;rsquo;s release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to use 2 tablets at the same time like I&amp;rsquo;m doing, they have to share the same brand. In other words, you can&amp;rsquo;t use a flat Wacom tablet and a Wacom cintiq at the same time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDquest news and Krita 3.0 pre-alpha 3</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/community/GDquest-news-and-Krita-3.0-pre-alpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 08:25:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/community/GDquest-news-and-Krita-3.0-pre-alpha/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/JWwpm4hs0l0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Hi there! I wanted to keep you posted on what is going on right now with GDquest. The video says it all, but I’m going to sum up the news below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With one last contract finished last week, and the series on monster design done, I am now working full-time on Game Art Quest. My top priority is to release the first version of the GAQ Krita brush back and to finish chapter 0 in the training. Once this is done, I will start releasing videos from the training publicly, at the rate of 1 to 2 per week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I released the first 5 soundtracks from the project in an album called &lt;a href=&#34;https://gdquest.bandcamp.com/album/space-adventures&#34;&gt;Space Adventures&lt;/a&gt;. They are available under the &lt;strong&gt;Creative Commons 4.0 license&lt;/strong&gt;, so you can use them in &lt;strong&gt;both personal and commercial projects&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&#34;border: 0; width: 700px; height: 307px;&#34; src=&#34;https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1579881958/size=large/bgcol=333333/linkcol=e99708/artwork=small/transparent=true/&#34; seamless&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.bandcamp.com/album/space-adventures&#34;&gt;Space adventures by Nathan Lovato&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-votes-for-future-tutorials&#34;&gt;Your votes for future tutorials&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since January, I have been &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/post/community/vote-for-upcoming-tutorials-january-2016/&#34;&gt;running a vote&lt;/a&gt; to ask you which tutorial series you wanted me to do this year aside from Krita. More than 400 people voted, and here are the themes you picked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview of Godot 2.0, the open source game engine, for 2d games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Painting rock and grass tiles for 2d games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Human proportions, from reality to games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is great, as they will reinforce &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/&#34;&gt;Game Art Quest&lt;/a&gt;. I might also do the 4th one, the Overview of &lt;a href=&#34;http://superpowers-html5.com/&#34;&gt;Superpowers, the collaborative HTML5 game engine&lt;/a&gt;, as time permits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;krita-3-0-pre-alpha-3&#34;&gt;Krita 3.0, pre-alpha 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;\img\post\community\krita-gradient-map.png&#34; alt=&#34;Krita gradient map filter&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 3rd pre-alpha of Krita 3.0 was released! The development entered a feature-frozen state, and the full release of Krita 3.0 is planned for April 27. The features that didn’t make it in this version will be available in Krita 3.1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick list of what is new in this pre-alpha:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The improvements to the layer docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new grid and guides system, along with snapping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A gradient map filter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A greater alpha blending mode, useful for painting with the pixel brush engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The foundations for 2 exporters. One is for spriter, the animation application for 2d games, and the other one is a csv-based format to exports animated sequences from krita.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A variety of improvements to the move tool, the crop tool, the assistants…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Head on to the dedicated article on the official website to find the builds along with download instructions. It also features an exhaustive list of changes in this version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That’s it for this update. See you soon, in the next one!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vote for Upcoming Tutorials! January 2016</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/community/vote-for-upcoming-tutorials-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 09:16:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/community/vote-for-upcoming-tutorials-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Up until now, the tutorials have been a bit random on GDquest. I jumped from theme to theme based on your requests or ideas I had. But now, we&amp;rsquo;re in 2016. I want us to try something new. &lt;strong&gt;It is time for you, members of the community, to choose the tutorial series you want to see on the channel.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose a handful of ideas based on your feedback and on what I can handle right now. There are 2 themes that I didn’t list, on purpose: animation and the Godot engine. Here&amp;rsquo;s why: there will be some animation tutorials when Krita 3.0 is released. And I am waiting for Godot 2.0 to cover it on the channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;let-your-voice-be-heard&#34;&gt;Let your voice be heard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can pick as many series as you’d like! I will produce the 3 most popular entries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gdquest.typeform.com/to/HfiMXO&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
&lt;button type=&#34;button&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-lg btn-default center-block&#34;&gt;
    Click here to Vote!
&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find more information about each and every series below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/superpowers-html5.png&#34; alt=&#34;Superpowers, the collaborative HTML5 game engine tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview-of-superpowers-the-collaborative-html5-game-engine&#34;&gt;Overview of Superpowers, the collaborative HTML5 game engine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Superpowers is a fully functional 2-D and 3-D HTML5 game editor that was released a few days ago, free and open source. It is based on three.JS and it uses Typescript, a superset of JavaScript. Not only that, it allows you to collaborate on projects online in real time! Although it is still young, the toolset is already impressive. In the development team is already at work on exciting new features!
By the way, it’s not their first shot at game engines. The project is made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://sparklinlabs.com/&#34;&gt;Sparkin Labs&lt;/a&gt;, the authors of &lt;a href=&#34;http://craftstud.io/&#34;&gt;CraftStudio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/godot-2d-engine.png&#34; alt=&#34;Human proportions, from reality to games tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview-of-godot-2-0-the-open-source-game-engine-for-2d-games&#34;&gt;Overview of Godot 2.0, the open source game engine, for 2d games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.godotengine.org/projects/godot-engine&#34;&gt;Godot&lt;/a&gt; is an open source 2d and 3d game engine. It was developed in-house by an Argentinian game studio, Okam, and released open source 2 years ago. Godot 2.0 features a robust editor with built-in animation tools, a visual shader editor, and much more!
In this series, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover the basics of 2d game development with Godot. If you want to join the community, check out its &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/godotengine/&#34;&gt;Facebook group&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/human-proportions-from-reality-to-games.png&#34; alt=&#34;Human proportions, from reality to games tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;human-proportions-from-reality-to-games&#34;&gt;Human proportions, from reality to games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of tutorials available on the basics of human anatomy and proportions (I recommend &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/user/ProkoTV&#34;&gt;Proko&amp;rsquo;s videos&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here though, I want to create a series unlike most of what you&amp;rsquo;ll find online. We will take a look at the general proportions of human beings. We will look at both male and female. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover some critical landmarks of the human body. We will then compare it with the proportions of children, and teenagers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But more importantly, we will then discuss how we can play with those proportions in games. We&amp;rsquo;ll look at what rules designers break, and which ones they respect. We will look at various examples of stylized characters in popular games, and we will then work on our own character thumbnails. It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty big topic, perfect to complement Game Art Quest!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/blender-vse.png&#34; alt=&#34;Blender VSE tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction-to-video-editing-with-blender&#34;&gt;Introduction to video editing with Blender&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blender is an impressive piece of software. It is also my open source replacement for After Effects and a video editing tool of choice. Its sequencer has its shortcomings, but it is an efficient tool to get started making videos nonetheless. In this series, I will share what I have learned creating YouTube videos with blender for the past 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/becoming-a-game-designer.png&#34; alt=&#34;Becoming a game designer tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;becoming-an-independent-game-designer&#34;&gt;Becoming an independent game designer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a game designer? How can you become a professional or an independent game designer? Based on my experience creating games with a talented engineer, working as a freelancer and now creating Game Design Quest, I will share what I learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t tell you which college you should pick, but I can help you to teach yourself game design. That is what this series is all about. &lt;strong&gt;It is not a series about creating a business and selling your games!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/introduction-music-scoring-for-games.png&#34; alt=&#34;Introduction to music scoring for games tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-primer-on-music-scoring-for-games&#34;&gt;A primer on music scoring for games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, but I write and produce &lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/gdquest&#34;&gt;game soundtracks&lt;/a&gt;! I actually studied music scoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing good music takes a lot of experience! And the resources for it are sometimes overly complicated, or plain mystical. I was lucky to learn music with a teacher who’s all about analysis and clarity. I&amp;rsquo;d like to share some of what he taught me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/243108339&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This isn’t a series about music production using a DAW&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Digital Audio Workstation&lt;/em&gt;) like FL studio. Music scoring is a huge topic. This is but an introduction to music as a language! I will try to give you a good sense of what the building blocks of a score are, and what scoring for games is like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/rock-and-grass-tiles.png&#34; alt=&#34;Rock tiles tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;painting-rock-and-grass-tiles-for-2d-games&#34;&gt;Painting rock and grass tiles for 2d games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one type of 2-D game asset that is rarely explained online: tiles. These are sprites that connect seamlessly to one another and that you can reuse extensively to create your game backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial series, I will show you how to create tiles for the ground and for walls or hanging ceiling in an outdoor environment, in a side scrolling game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/kickstarter-tips.png&#34; alt=&#34;Game Art Quest Kickstarter tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;kickstarter-all-of-my-hard-learned-tips&#34;&gt;Kickstarter: all of my hard learned tips!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you know I ran a Kickstarter campaign that was successfully funded. Better than that, it doubled the initial goal! During those hectic weeks, struggling to keep up with the frightening workload, I learned a lot about crowdfunding. With this theme, I want to go over the preparation, the ongoing production and the communication you have to take care of during the course of a Kickstarter campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phaser auto completion in Atom</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/programming/phaser-auto-completion-in-atom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/programming/phaser-auto-completion-in-atom/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This little guide will show you how to use the tern-phaser plugin by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/angelozerr&#34;&gt;Angelo&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;http://atom.io&#34;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;installing-tern&#34;&gt;Installing tern&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first part explains how to get npm, install tern and the tern-phaser plugin. The first thing that you need to ensure is that you have Node.js installed on your computer. You can download it on &lt;a href=&#34;https://nodejs.org/en/&#34;&gt;https://nodejs.org/en/&lt;/a&gt;. This will give you access to npm as well, a handy package manager for js libraries and plugins. It allows you to download install all sorts of packages from the command prompt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once Node.js has finished installing, we have a few commands to call from the command prompt. On windows, you can access the command line need to press the Windows R key combination, type &amp;#8220;cmd&amp;#8221; and press enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/HVB8KRn.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we need to install a few packages. First, there is tern, the JS analyzer that the tern-phaser plugin uses. In the command line tool, type &amp;#8220;npm install tern&amp;#8221; and press enter. Npm will take care of the install for you, it will just take a moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/H1xIdew.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then need the tern-phaser plugin to be installed where the tern package has been put. You can let windows find the folder for you by typing &amp;#8220;npm install -g tern-phaser&amp;#8221; in the command prompt and pressing enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/qqUNi8c.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-manual-route&#34;&gt;The manual route&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If the automatic install of tern-phaser doesn&amp;#8217;t work&lt;/strong&gt;, you&amp;#8217;ll have to go navigate to the tern install folder manually from the command prompt. To change the folder the command prompt is in, you need to type cd (&lt;em&gt;current directory&lt;/em&gt;) followed by the path you want to reach. By default, tern should be installed to C:\Users**YourName**\AppData\Roaming\npm\node_modules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the command prompt, you then have to enter &amp;#8220;cd C:\Users**YourName**\AppData\Roaming\npm\node_modules&amp;#8221;. Note that you can copy the path from windows and paste it in the command prompt using the right mouse button (&lt;em&gt;Ctrl V doesn&amp;#8217;t work by default&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/4shbnrB.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/rX9oAKb.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Right click on the command line tool to paste text.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you got to the right folder, just type npm &amp;#8220;install tern-phaser&amp;#8221; and press enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/zJusEnO.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Without -g, the command installs the tern-phaser package in the folder you&amp;#8217;re currently in.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;using-tern-phaser-with-atom&#34;&gt;Using tern-phaser with Atom&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, you have both tern and tern-phaser installed on your computer. Let&amp;#8217;s move to setting up atom to work with tern. There is no native integration of tern in atom. However, there is a plugin called &lt;strong&gt;atom-ternjs&lt;/strong&gt; that works like a charm. We can install the package from the command line as well. Either &lt;strong&gt;close and reopen the command&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;prompt&lt;/strong&gt; or navigate back to your root folder with the following command: &amp;#8220;cd C:\Users\YourName&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, to call the Atom Package Manager, you need to use the apm command. Type &amp;#8220;apm install atom-ternjs&amp;#8221; and press enter. This will add this package to atom for you. To use tern with your project, you just need to have a tern configuration file. Atom-ternjs can create a basic config file for you. In Atom, you first need to have at least one javascript file loaded. Then, go to packages -&amp;gt; Atom ternjs -&amp;gt; Configure project&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/QjFJpud.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can set some parameters in the newly opened tab and click on save and restart server. This will create a new .tern-project file in your project folder. We still need to tell it to use the phaser plugin. You just have to add &amp;#8220;phaser&amp;#8221; in the plugins section. Here&amp;#8217;s the content of my .tern-project file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
    {   &amp;#8220;ecmaVersion&amp;#8221;: 5,   &amp;#8220;libs&amp;#8221;: [&amp;#8220;browser&amp;#8221;],   &amp;#8220;plugins&amp;#8221;: {     &amp;#8220;phaser&amp;#8221;: {}   } }
  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/EC06Yl4.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save your file, and then go to package -&amp;gt; Atom Ternjs -&amp;gt; Restart server. If you don&amp;#8217;t get any error, you&amp;#8217;re good to go! &lt;em&gt;Note that having a phaser.js file next to your .tern-project file can prevent tern-phaser from working &amp;#8211; in which case you&amp;#8217;ll get a series of errors in Atom&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/Fd9QqM3.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>