<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community on GDquest</title>
    <link>http://gdquest.com/tags/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community on GDquest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 11:17:06 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://gdquest.com/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>June update: the Randa meetings</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/06/kickstarter-news-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 11:17:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/06/kickstarter-news-june/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re getting to the end of June. It&amp;rsquo;s time to sum up all that&amp;rsquo;s been happening this month. The short version: I kept improving the website, went to the biggest yearly KDE development sprint in Randa, Switzerland, and added about 1h of tutorials dedicated to Krita 3&amp;rsquo;s new features in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/volume-1/krita-tutorial-for-game-artists/&#34;&gt;Krita training&lt;/a&gt;. You can find more details about what happened in Randa, and what the plans are for July, below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;randa&#34;&gt;Randa&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From June 13 to 19, I was in Randa, KDE&amp;rsquo;s biggest yearly sprint. KDE is a large community of free software developers and users. Krita is part of it, and it&amp;rsquo;s certainly the most popular multiplatform KDE program today. Sadly, no one else from the team could make it to the sprint this year. They ran a hectic Kickstarter in May, and boud, Krita&amp;rsquo;s maintainer, had too much work to do the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Randa was an amazing experience for me. There, I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to produce Krita tutorials. I mostly jumped around projects, learned about the whole KDE ecosystem, and helped with communication and UX design. It&amp;rsquo;s incredible to get in touch with so many cultures at once. People came from all around the world. There was Joseph, from Kenya, who came to port KDEnlive on Windows. Lays and Ayrton, from Brazil, working on an open 3d printing program. Developers from India, Germany, Denmark&amp;hellip; you name it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2016/06/Randa-meetings-work-discussions.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;KDE Randa meetings: developers discussions&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All those people are so different&amp;hellip; and yet they all work together to hopefully make the computer world a slightly better place. There was such a strong ambience there that we all worked very hard. I was up around 7:00 every morning, and went off to bed at 23:00. I spent the vast majority of the day working. And it was pretty much the same for everybody else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The village we stayed at itself was peaceful and lovely. A perfect, undistracted place to both focus and relax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2016/06/Randa-view-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Randa view of the mountains&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The view was gorgeous from my office&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;time-to-make-some-money-again&#34;&gt;Time to make some money again&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I told you in a previous update, Game Art Quest became bigger than what it was supposed to be. With the Kickstarter, we raised enough money for six months of full-time work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These six months are getting to an end, so I have to make a bit of money again. I&amp;rsquo;m getting new offers on a weekly basis, but until now, I almost declined them all. However, I accepted one job writing Krita tutorials for a magazine this month. It is a great opportunity as they asked me to work on animation, which I haven&amp;rsquo;t covered yet in the training, thus it&amp;rsquo;s not distracting me from daily work too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking to start working on and selling the next 2 volumes of the training in early access at the end of July. If I sell enough, I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to keep working full-time on it. Otherwise, I&amp;rsquo;ll dedicate one day per week to client work, which shouldn&amp;rsquo;t slow down the production of the training noticeably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-video-a-week&#34;&gt;One video a week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s summer time in here. The hot weather is back, and people are taking time off. I&amp;rsquo;m not! I&amp;rsquo;ll be here all summer long, working at the same pace. However, now that the tutorial series covering Krita 3&amp;rsquo;s new features is out, we&amp;rsquo;re going to move back to a rhythm of 1 tutorial per week on the channel. This will give me more time to improve the GDquest Blender add-on, and to prepare the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/post/community/vote-for-upcoming-tutorials-january-2016/&#34;&gt;future series&lt;/a&gt; coming to the channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-week&#34;&gt;This week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To wrap up June, I have to release a brush pack update. This new version will contain 4 new brushes, and I painted a new thumbnail for the blender brush, as the current one looks horrible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2016/06/Flat-blender-brush.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;New flat blender brush icon&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I&amp;rsquo;m working on the fourth chapter in the Krita training, to release it as soon as possible. It will introduce you to the game assets creation workflow. As soon as it is out, I will move on to the second volume of the training, which you will be able to access on Gumroad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving into July, I have to get working again on the blender of VSE add-on. It is one of the main ways I can improve my productivity creating the video tutorials now. My goal is to add one new feature every single week, even if it&amp;rsquo;s small. This week for instance, I&amp;rsquo;m working on an import feature that loads all of the project&amp;rsquo;s video and audio files to the VSE in one click. As I get to create up to six videos in a single week, this feature will be a real time saver. And with that, I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to release the first public version of the add-on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2016/06/blender-vse-add-on-code.png&#34; alt=&#34;Blender GDquest VSE add-on import code&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The import code is already there - it just needs to be refined&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, it&amp;rsquo;s time to get back to work! Thank you all for reading. Thank you for constant support and your kind words. I read all of your comments on Youtube, on social networks, and the messages you send me via email. It&amp;rsquo;s really heartwarming to see some of you following everything that&amp;rsquo;s happening on a weekly basis. Big thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May update: Krita brushes and ConciseCSS</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/05/new-website-and-krita-brushes-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 13:11:19 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/05/new-website-and-krita-brushes-update/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;May has been a busy month. I did my best to keep up with everyone on social networks, to give a hand to the Krita developers, with their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AjIiI8uiVNM&#34;&gt;Kickstarter campaign&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip; But I didn&amp;rsquo;t take the time to write longer news posts like this one. Time to share the news for this month!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, I&amp;rsquo;m still catching up with work, since I got that shoulder injury. Thankfully, I got faster in some areas, especially answering people online, thus I&amp;rsquo;m making good progress. On to the news!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div row column=12&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;card&#34;&gt;
    
    &lt;div class=&#34;card-image&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2016/05/krita-logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Featured picture&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    

    
    &lt;h3 class=&#34;card-title&#34;&gt;
      Krita 3 launch Youtube livestream
    &lt;/h3&gt;
    

    
    &lt;div class=&#34;card-content&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
        Krita 3 is out tomorrow! I will be live on YouTube to answer all of your questions about the program, GDquest, and game art in general. I will also create 2-D game assets to fill in the blanks. To join the event, click on the link below and show up tomorrow, at 6 PM &lt;abbr title=&#34;Central Europe Standard Time (UTC/GMT +2)&#34;&gt;CEST&lt;/abbr&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    

    
    &lt;div class=&#34;card-footer lead&#34; style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hlcHDRc-gN8&#34;&gt;
        Youtube Livestream
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;krita-brushes-may-update&#34;&gt;Krita brushes May update&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you know, I&amp;rsquo;ve made a set of &lt;a href=&#34;https://gum.co/krita-brushes-for-game-artists&#34;&gt;Krita brushes for game artists&lt;/a&gt;, available on Gumroad. It was initially meant to just be a simple brush pack, I started adding video tutorials on top of it last week to explain what each preset was designed for. This month&amp;rsquo;s update adds 2 new blending brushes: both a round and a flat one. These work a bit like the regular mixing brushes, but they only blend existing colors on the selected layer. They are way softer than existing presets to help you shade extremely smooth surfaces like silk, skin, clouds, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2016/05/krita-brushes-update-may-2016.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Picture: The brushes on the pop-up palette&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will now find 2 tutorials along with the brushes. The first one is dedicated to the mix brushes, and it will show you how to play with the opacity setting to get the most out of them. The 2nd one explains how to use the smear brushes in practice. They may seem strange at first, but trust me, they are actually quite useful! On top of that, I updated the existing brushes to make them less resource intensive. The Paint_Painterly preset comes with a new custom brush tip, and it should be at least 3 or 4 times faster now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gdquest-s-upgrade&#34;&gt;Gdquest&amp;rsquo;s upgrade&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new version of the website is available! I ported it to a new SASS framework, &lt;a href=&#34;http://concisecss.com/&#34;&gt;ConciseCSS&lt;/a&gt;. Some things have changed visually, hopefully for the better. But more importantly, under the hood, everything is different. With the same functionality, the website&amp;rsquo;s Go templates are about 20% shorter. The CSS is smaller, and now I have full control over everything. Not only was the port fast to do, but now I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to improve GDquest faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before that, I was using &lt;a href=&#34;http://getbootstrap.com/&#34;&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;, one of the most popular frameworks out there, made by Twitter. It is very good, but it&amp;rsquo;s also huge. It has everything you&amp;rsquo;d ever need, as well as everything you would never need. Because of that, customizing the style of your website can take a lot of time. That&amp;rsquo;s why I switched to Concise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting with the next version, I will also release the website&amp;rsquo;s code open source. That way, those of you who want a powerful system to create a tutorial/blog oriented website will have an option based on Hugo, a blazing fast, open source static website engine. Right now, the website handles posts, course pages, course summaries, and has some simple modules if you&amp;rsquo;d like to create a blog page for instance. The next version will add templates to render a to do list, to render FAQs, to create a landing page, but also to create a tutorial/articles library!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;next-up&#34;&gt;Next up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;June is going to be a busy month! From June 13 to 19, I&amp;rsquo;ll be at the Randa meetings in Switzerland to work on Krita education, and to meet dozens of passionate KDE developers. The Randa meetings are a yearly open source development sprint. Developers gather from all around the world and share experience with one another to push their respective projects forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that Krita 3 is coming out, I&amp;rsquo;m focusing on video tutorials dedicated to the new version. I plan to create about a dozen. Then, I&amp;rsquo;ll move on to chapter 3 of the Krita tutorial for game artists, which will run you through the game assets creation workflow. This chapter is going to be an entire little training in itself, and a great occasion to put everything you&amp;rsquo;ve learned so far in the training in practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wraps up this month&amp;rsquo;s update. Thank you kindly for your time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;See you soon,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nathan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PS: Don&amp;rsquo;t forget the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/krita/krita-2016-lets-make-text-and-vector-art-awesome&#34;&gt;Krita 2016 Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;. It ends in 8 days.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDquest news and Krita 3.0 pre-alpha 3</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/community/GDquest-news-and-Krita-3.0-pre-alpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 08:25:29 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/community/GDquest-news-and-Krita-3.0-pre-alpha/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/JWwpm4hs0l0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Hi there! I wanted to keep you posted on what is going on right now with GDquest. The video says it all, but I’m going to sum up the news below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With one last contract finished last week, and the series on monster design done, I am now working full-time on Game Art Quest. My top priority is to release the first version of the GAQ Krita brush back and to finish chapter 0 in the training. Once this is done, I will start releasing videos from the training publicly, at the rate of 1 to 2 per week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I released the first 5 soundtracks from the project in an album called &lt;a href=&#34;https://gdquest.bandcamp.com/album/space-adventures&#34;&gt;Space Adventures&lt;/a&gt;. They are available under the &lt;strong&gt;Creative Commons 4.0 license&lt;/strong&gt;, so you can use them in &lt;strong&gt;both personal and commercial projects&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&#34;border: 0; width: 700px; height: 307px;&#34; src=&#34;https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1579881958/size=large/bgcol=333333/linkcol=e99708/artwork=small/transparent=true/&#34; seamless&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.bandcamp.com/album/space-adventures&#34;&gt;Space adventures by Nathan Lovato&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-votes-for-future-tutorials&#34;&gt;Your votes for future tutorials&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since January, I have been &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/post/community/vote-for-upcoming-tutorials-january-2016/&#34;&gt;running a vote&lt;/a&gt; to ask you which tutorial series you wanted me to do this year aside from Krita. More than 400 people voted, and here are the themes you picked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview of Godot 2.0, the open source game engine, for 2d games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Painting rock and grass tiles for 2d games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Human proportions, from reality to games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is great, as they will reinforce &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/game-art-quest/&#34;&gt;Game Art Quest&lt;/a&gt;. I might also do the 4th one, the Overview of &lt;a href=&#34;http://superpowers-html5.com/&#34;&gt;Superpowers, the collaborative HTML5 game engine&lt;/a&gt;, as time permits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;krita-3-0-pre-alpha-3&#34;&gt;Krita 3.0, pre-alpha 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;\img\post\community\krita-gradient-map.png&#34; alt=&#34;Krita gradient map filter&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 3rd pre-alpha of Krita 3.0 was released! The development entered a feature-frozen state, and the full release of Krita 3.0 is planned for April 27. The features that didn’t make it in this version will be available in Krita 3.1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick list of what is new in this pre-alpha:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The improvements to the layer docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new grid and guides system, along with snapping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A gradient map filter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A greater alpha blending mode, useful for painting with the pixel brush engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The foundations for 2 exporters. One is for spriter, the animation application for 2d games, and the other one is a csv-based format to exports animated sequences from krita.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A variety of improvements to the move tool, the crop tool, the assistants…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Head on to the dedicated article on the official website to find the builds along with download instructions. It also features an exhaustive list of changes in this version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That’s it for this update. See you soon, in the next one!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vote for future free tutorials! 2016</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/community/vote-for-upcoming-tutorials-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 09:16:10 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/community/vote-for-upcoming-tutorials-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;06-2016 update: Voting is over! You were more than 400 to vote on the series you want to see on GDquest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the top 3 results:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview of Godot 2&lt;/strong&gt; (249 votes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Painting rock and grass tiles for 2d games&lt;/strong&gt; (141 votes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Human proportions, from reality to games&lt;/strong&gt; (119 votes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;let-your-voice-be-heard&#34;&gt;Let your voice be heard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up until now, the tutorials have been a bit random on GDquest. I jumped from theme to theme based on your requests or ideas I had. But now, we&amp;rsquo;re in 2016. I want us to try something new. &lt;strong&gt;It is time for you, members of the community, to choose the tutorial series you want to see on the channel.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose a handful of ideas based on your feedback and on what I can handle right now. There are 2 themes that I didn’t list, on purpose: animation and the Godot engine. Here&amp;rsquo;s why: there will be some animation tutorials when Krita 3.0 is released. And I am waiting for Godot 2.0 to cover it on the channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can pick as many series as you’d like! I will produce the 3 most popular entries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find more information about each and every series below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/superpowers-html5.png&#34; alt=&#34;Superpowers, the collaborative HTML5 game engine tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview-of-superpowers-the-collaborative-html5-game-engine&#34;&gt;Overview of Superpowers, the collaborative HTML5 game engine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Superpowers is a fully functional 2-D and 3-D HTML5 game editor that was released a few days ago, free and open source. It is based on three.JS and it uses Typescript, a superset of JavaScript. Not only that, it allows you to collaborate on projects online in real time! Although it is still young, the toolset is already impressive. In the development team is already at work on exciting new features!
By the way, it’s not their first shot at game engines. The project is made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://sparklinlabs.com/&#34;&gt;Sparkin Labs&lt;/a&gt;, the authors of &lt;a href=&#34;http://craftstud.io/&#34;&gt;CraftStudio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/godot-2d-engine.png&#34; alt=&#34;Human proportions, from reality to games tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview-of-godot-2-0-the-open-source-game-engine-for-2d-games&#34;&gt;Overview of Godot 2.0, the open source game engine, for 2d games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.godotengine.org/projects/godot-engine&#34;&gt;Godot&lt;/a&gt; is an open source 2d and 3d game engine. It was developed in-house by an Argentinian game studio, Okam, and released open source 2 years ago. Godot 2.0 features a robust editor with built-in animation tools, a visual shader editor, and much more!
In this series, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover the basics of 2d game development with Godot. If you want to join the community, check out its &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/godotengine/&#34;&gt;Facebook group&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/human-proportions-from-reality-to-games.png&#34; alt=&#34;Human proportions, from reality to games tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;human-proportions-from-reality-to-games&#34;&gt;Human proportions, from reality to games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of tutorials available on the basics of human anatomy and proportions (I recommend &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/user/ProkoTV&#34;&gt;Proko&amp;rsquo;s videos&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here though, I want to create a series unlike most of what you&amp;rsquo;ll find online. We will take a look at the general proportions of human beings. We will look at both male and female. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover some critical landmarks of the human body. We will then compare it with the proportions of children, and teenagers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But more importantly, we will then discuss how we can play with those proportions in games. We&amp;rsquo;ll look at what rules designers break, and which ones they respect. We will look at various examples of stylized characters in popular games, and we will then work on our own character thumbnails. It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty big topic, perfect to complement Game Art Quest!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/blender-vse.png&#34; alt=&#34;Blender VSE tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction-to-video-editing-with-blender&#34;&gt;Introduction to video editing with Blender&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blender is an impressive piece of software. It is also my open source replacement for After Effects and a video editing tool of choice. Its sequencer has its shortcomings, but it is an efficient tool to get started making videos nonetheless. In this series, I will share what I have learned creating YouTube videos with blender for the past 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/becoming-a-game-designer.png&#34; alt=&#34;Becoming a game designer tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;becoming-an-independent-game-designer&#34;&gt;Becoming an independent game designer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a game designer? How can you become a professional or an independent game designer? Based on my experience creating games with a talented engineer, working as a freelancer and now creating Game Design Quest, I will share what I learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t tell you which college you should pick, but I can help you to teach yourself game design. That is what this series is all about. &lt;strong&gt;It is not a series about creating a business and selling your games!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/introduction-music-scoring-for-games.png&#34; alt=&#34;Introduction to music scoring for games tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-primer-on-music-scoring-for-games&#34;&gt;A primer on music scoring for games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, but I write and produce &lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/gdquest&#34;&gt;game soundtracks&lt;/a&gt;! I actually studied music scoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing good music takes a lot of experience! And the resources for it are sometimes overly complicated, or plain mystical. I was lucky to learn music with a teacher who’s all about analysis and clarity. I&amp;rsquo;d like to share some of what he taught me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/243108339&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This isn’t a series about music production using a DAW&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Digital Audio Workstation&lt;/em&gt;) like FL studio. Music scoring is a huge topic. This is but an introduction to music as a language! I will try to give you a good sense of what the building blocks of a score are, and what scoring for games is like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/rock-and-grass-tiles.png&#34; alt=&#34;Rock tiles tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;painting-rock-and-grass-tiles-for-2d-games&#34;&gt;Painting rock and grass tiles for 2d games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one type of 2-D game asset that is rarely explained online: tiles. These are sprites that connect seamlessly to one another and that you can reuse extensively to create your game backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial series, I will show you how to create tiles for the ground and for walls or hanging ceiling in an outdoor environment, in a side scrolling game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/Tutorials/Banners/Small/kickstarter-tips.png&#34; alt=&#34;Game Art Quest Kickstarter tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;kickstarter-all-of-my-hard-learned-tips&#34;&gt;Kickstarter: all of my hard learned tips!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you know I ran a Kickstarter campaign that was successfully funded. Better than that, it doubled the initial goal! During those hectic weeks, struggling to keep up with the frightening workload, I learned a lot about crowdfunding. With this theme, I want to go over the preparation, the ongoing production and the communication you have to take care of during the course of a Kickstarter campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>