<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GDquest</title>
    <link>http://gdquest.com/category/community/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on GDquest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://gdquest.com/category/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Vote for future free tutorials! 2016</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/community/vote-for-upcoming-tutorials-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 09:16:10 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/community/vote-for-upcoming-tutorials-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;06-2016 update: Voting is over! You were more than 400 to vote on the series you want to see on GDquest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the top 3 results:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview of Godot 2&lt;/strong&gt; (249 votes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Painting rock and grass tiles for 2d games&lt;/strong&gt; (141 votes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Human proportions, from reality to games&lt;/strong&gt; (119 votes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;let-your-voice-be-heard&#34;&gt;Let your voice be heard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up until now, the tutorials have been a bit random on GDquest. I jumped from theme to theme based on your requests or ideas I had. But now, we&amp;rsquo;re in 2016. I want us to try something new. &lt;strong&gt;It is time for you, members of the community, to choose the tutorial series you want to see on the channel.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose a handful of ideas based on your feedback and on what I can handle right now. There are 2 themes that I didn’t list, on purpose: animation and the Godot engine. Here&amp;rsquo;s why: there will be some animation tutorials when Krita 3.0 is released. And I am waiting for Godot 2.0 to cover it on the channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can pick as many series as you’d like! I will produce the 3 most popular entries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find more information about each and every series below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/community/tutorial-banners/superpowers-html5.png&#34; alt=&#34;Superpowers, the collaborative HTML5 game engine tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview-of-superpowers-the-collaborative-html5-game-engine&#34;&gt;Overview of Superpowers, the collaborative HTML5 game engine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Superpowers is a fully functional 2-D and 3-D HTML5 game editor that was released a few days ago, free and open source. It is based on three.JS and it uses Typescript, a superset of JavaScript. Not only that, it allows you to collaborate on projects online in real time! Although it is still young, the toolset is already impressive. In the development team is already at work on exciting new features!
By the way, it’s not their first shot at game engines. The project is made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://sparklinlabs.com/&#34;&gt;Sparkin Labs&lt;/a&gt;, the authors of &lt;a href=&#34;http://craftstud.io/&#34;&gt;CraftStudio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/community/tutorial-banners/godot-2d-engine.png&#34; alt=&#34;Human proportions, from reality to games tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview-of-godot-2-0-the-open-source-game-engine-for-2d-games&#34;&gt;Overview of Godot 2.0, the open source game engine, for 2d games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.godotengine.org/projects/godot-engine&#34;&gt;Godot&lt;/a&gt; is an open source 2d and 3d game engine. It was developed in-house by an Argentinian game studio, Okam, and released open source 2 years ago. Godot 2.0 features a robust editor with built-in animation tools, a visual shader editor, and much more!
In this series, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover the basics of 2d game development with Godot. If you want to join the community, check out its &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/godotengine/&#34;&gt;Facebook group&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/community/tutorial-banners/human-proportions-from-reality-to-games.png&#34; alt=&#34;Human proportions, from reality to games tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;human-proportions-from-reality-to-games&#34;&gt;Human proportions, from reality to games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of tutorials available on the basics of human anatomy and proportions (I recommend &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/user/ProkoTV&#34;&gt;Proko&amp;rsquo;s videos&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here though, I want to create a series unlike most of what you&amp;rsquo;ll find online. We will take a look at the general proportions of human beings. We will look at both male and female. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover some critical landmarks of the human body. We will then compare it with the proportions of children, and teenagers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But more importantly, we will then discuss how we can play with those proportions in games. We&amp;rsquo;ll look at what rules designers break, and which ones they respect. We will look at various examples of stylized characters in popular games, and we will then work on our own character thumbnails. It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty big topic, perfect to complement Game Art Quest!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/community/tutorial-banners/blender-vse.png&#34; alt=&#34;Blender VSE tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction-to-video-editing-with-blender&#34;&gt;Introduction to video editing with Blender&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blender is an impressive piece of software. It is also my open source replacement for After Effects and a video editing tool of choice. Its sequencer has its shortcomings, but it is an efficient tool to get started making videos nonetheless. In this series, I will share what I have learned creating YouTube videos with blender for the past 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/community/tutorial-banners/becoming-a-game-designer.png&#34; alt=&#34;Becoming a game designer tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;becoming-an-independent-game-designer&#34;&gt;Becoming an independent game designer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a game designer? How can you become a professional or an independent game designer? Based on my experience creating games with a talented engineer, working as a freelancer and now creating Game Design Quest, I will share what I learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t tell you which college you should pick, but I can help you to teach yourself game design. That is what this series is all about. &lt;strong&gt;It is not a series about creating a business and selling your games!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/community/tutorial-banners/introduction-music-scoring-for-games.png&#34; alt=&#34;Introduction to music scoring for games tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-primer-on-music-scoring-for-games&#34;&gt;A primer on music scoring for games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, but I write and produce &lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/gdquest&#34;&gt;game soundtracks&lt;/a&gt;! I actually studied music scoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing good music takes a lot of experience! And the resources for it are sometimes overly complicated, or plain mystical. I was lucky to learn music with a teacher who’s all about analysis and clarity. I&amp;rsquo;d like to share some of what he taught me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/243108339&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This isn’t a series about music production using a DAW&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Digital Audio Workstation&lt;/em&gt;) like FL studio. Music scoring is a huge topic. This is but an introduction to music as a language! I will try to give you a good sense of what the building blocks of a score are, and what scoring for games is like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/community/tutorial-banners/rock-and-grass-tiles.png&#34; alt=&#34;Rock tiles tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;painting-rock-and-grass-tiles-for-2d-games&#34;&gt;Painting rock and grass tiles for 2d games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one type of 2-D game asset that is rarely explained online: tiles. These are sprites that connect seamlessly to one another and that you can reuse extensively to create your game backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial series, I will show you how to create tiles for the ground and for walls or hanging ceiling in an outdoor environment, in a side scrolling game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/community/tutorial-banners/kickstarter-tips.png&#34; alt=&#34;Game Art Quest Kickstarter tutorial banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;kickstarter-all-of-my-hard-learned-tips&#34;&gt;Kickstarter: all of my hard learned tips!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you know I ran a Kickstarter campaign that was successfully funded. Better than that, it doubled the initial goal! During those hectic weeks, struggling to keep up with the frightening workload, I learned a lot about crowdfunding. With this theme, I want to go over the preparation, the ongoing production and the communication you have to take care of during the course of a Kickstarter campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>